Hasta El Fuego. Please hold.
Hasta El Fuego, ne quittez pas.
This way.
Suivez-moi.
-Another shot? -Yeah, sure. Okay.
- Un autre ? - Oui.
-Hi, Reggie. Hello. -Laura, hi.
- Salut, Reggie. - Laura, bonsoir.
So nice to phone-meet you in this incredibly embarrassing way.
Ravi de te parler pour cette raison très gênante.
You know, no problem. It's fine.
C'est rien, t'en fais pas.
This is what I get for picking a trendy place with no sign out front, huh?
Ça m'appendra à choisir un lieu branché sans enseigne.
Yeah, why do they do that here?
Pourquoi ils font ça ?
[ Don't know. I've only been in the city for a few months.
Aucune idée. Je suis à New York depuis peu.
-Me too! No way! Yeah. -Oh, wow.
Moi aussi, c'est dingue !
Well, it's a very cool restaurant.
En attendant, c'est un resto très stylé.
-Is it on Hudson? -Yes.
- C'est sur Hudson Street ? - Oui.
-Am I on Hudson? -I don't know.
- Je suis sur Hudson ? - J'en sais rien.
[I am not on Hudson. Shit.
Je suis pas dans cette rue, merde.
I am now walking towards Hudson.
Je marche vers Hudson.
-Okay. -/ am so, so sorry.
Désolé.
This is not the first impression I wanted to make on a college professor.
C'est pas comme ça qu'on impressionne une prof de fac.
Associate Professor, and it's just Film Studies...
Je donne juste des cours en études de cinéma.
so you're safe.
T'as rien à craindre.
Film Studies? That's cool.
Études de cinéma ? C'est cool.
You say that, but try teaching a class on 20th-century slashers
Imagine faire cours sur les slashers du 20e siècle
to a heap of hungover 19-year-olds.
à des étudiants en gueule de bois.
Slashers, huh? What's your favorite scary movie?
Les slashers ? C'est quoi, ton film d'horreur préféré ?
Not that one.
Pas celui-là.
So, why slashers?
Pourquoi les slashers ?
Well, I just-- You know, I think it's interesting.
Je les trouve intéressants.
You can really examine the culture of the moment
Ils reflètent la culture contemporaine
by looking at the tropes of the time.
à travers certains tropes
Like the masked killer, the final girl, the different rules:
comme le tueur masqué, la final girl, les règles du type :
Don't split up. Don't have sex.
ne pas se séparer, ne pas coucher...
-Don't answer the phone. -Exactly, exactly, exactly.
- Ne pas répondre au téléphone. - C'est ça.
It's all cliché.
C'est que des clichés,
But out of those clichés comes an opportunity for outsider art.
mais ils sont réinvestis par de nouveaux auteurs.
A voice for the voiceless, you might say.
Ils sont la voix de ceux qui n'en ont pas.
Yeah, I'm more of a rom-com guy, to be honest.
Moi, je préfère les comédies romantiques.
-Okay, I think I'm on Hudson. -Okay.
Bon, j'ai trouvé Hudson Street.
What color is the outside of the restaurant?
De quelle couleur est la façade du resto ?
I think it's red.
Rouge, je crois.
I don't see anything red.
Je vois rien de rouge.
I could be wrong. Let me just...
Je me trompe peut-être, attends.
Let me go have a little look-see.
Je vais aller jeter un œil.
Okay. Thank you.
Merci.
Yep, it's definitely red.
Oui, la façade est bien rouge.
Yeah, I'm not seeing anything red here.
Je vois rien de rouge, par ici.
Sure you're on Hudson?
Tu es bien sur Hudson ?
Crap, I'm still a block over.
Mince, c'est la rue d'après.
It looks like there's an alley [ can cut through.
Je peux couper par une ruelle.
ls the restaurant near an alley ?
Tu en vois une ?
Yes! Yes. There is an alley.
Oui, je vois une ruelle.
Perfect. I'm coming down the alley.
Super. J'arrive par là.
I don't see you.
Je te vois pas.
Wait. Really? Are you sure?
C'est vrai ? Tu es sûre ?
There are some dumpsters about halfway down.
Il y a des poubelles à mi-chemin.
I see them, but I don't see you.
Je les vois, mais pas toi.
Yeah, I don't see you, either.
Je te vois pas non plus.
This is creepy, right?
C'est un peu flippant, non ?
A little bit.
Un peu.
20th-century slashers, huh?
Les slashers du 20e siècle...
Yeah. Are you sure you're walking towards Hudson?
Tu es sûr d'aller vers Hudson ?
I'm sure.
Oui.
Oh, wait, I think I see you! Can you wave?
Je crois que je te vois. Tu me fais un signe ?
Can you see me?
Tu me vois ?
The person I'm looking at isn't waving. They're just... staring at me.
La personne que je vois ne bouge pas. Elle me fixe.
Are you sure?
T'es sûr ?
Okay, this is weird.
C'est bizarre.
Now they're moving towards me.
La personne vient vers moi.
Are you okay?
Tout va bien ?
Shit. He's following me.
Merde, il me suit.
I don't see anybody.
Je vois personne.
Holy shit, he's after me!
Putain, il va s'en prendre à moi !
Where are you?
T'es où ?
-He's got a knife! -What?
- Il a un couteau ! - Quoi ?
And that's not the worst part.
Mais c'est pas le pire.
The worst part is...
Le pire,
you teach a class about slashers
c'est que tu donnes un cours sur les slashers,
and you still walked info a dark alley. Alone.
mais que tu entres quand même dans une ruelle sombre, seule.
Okay, that's not funny.
C'est pas drôle.
No.
Non,
It's not.
en effet.
Now I see something red.
Maintenant, je vois du rouge.
Oh, hey. Tara!
Salut, Tara.
Jason.
Jason.
Are you and Greg gonna come to the OKB party?
Greg et toi venez à la soirée ?
Well, if he finishes his Spanish project in time, yes, we will.
S'il finit son devoir d'espagnol, oui.
Is your sister coming?
Ta sœur sera là ?
No, Sam wouldn't be caught dead at a frat party.
Sam préfère mourir qu'aller à ces fêtes.
There's a first time for everything.
Y a une première fois à tout.
Not tonight, though.
Pas ce soir.
-Can't convince her? -That's not my problem, that's yours.
- Tu peux la convaincre ? - C'est ton problème, ça.
-Save me a drink! -All right. I'll see you.
- Garde-moi un verre. - Ça marche. À plus.
Honey, I'm home!
Mon chou, je suis rentré !
Greg?
Greg ?
I'm sorry, okay?
Écoute, je suis désolé.
I just got massive blue balls, and I had to practice.
Ça me cassait les couilles d'attendre, je voulais m'entraîner.
Please don't be mad. How mad are you?
Sois pas vénère. T'es vénère ?
I'm not mad, Jason.
Je ne suis pas vénère, Jason.
Dude. We said we wouldn't use the voice on each other.
Vieux, on a dit qu'on faisait pas la voix entre nous.
We said a lot of things.
On a dit beaucoup de choses.
This is Greg, right?
C'est bien toi, Greg ?
Who else would it be?
Qui d'autre ça pourrait être ?
Where are you? I want to tell you about it.
T'es où ? Je veux te raconter.
Oh, by the way...
Au fait,
we should go to that frat party. Tara's going.
on devrait aller à cette soirée, Tara y sera.
-What was it like? -Not on the phone, man.
- Ça t'a fait quoi ? - Pas au téléphone.
And, seriously, turn off the fucking voice modulator!
Sérieux, éteins le modulateur.
I'm just trying to get the voice right.
Je m'entraîne à faire la voix.
You got to have your practice, I get mine.
Tu t'es entraîné. Maintenant, c'est mon tour.
Whatever.
Laisse tomber.
Just tell me what it felt like.
Dis-moi ce que ça t'a fait,
Then maybe I'll come out.
et je sortirai de ma cachette.
Dude, I know you're not here.
Je sais que t'es pas là.
Humor me.
Fais-moi plaisir.
All right, fine.
Bon, d'accord.
It was even better than we ever could have imagined.
C'était encore mieux que ce qu'on pouvait imaginer.
I mean, when the knife went in her,
Quand le couteau s'est enfoncé en elle,
it's like she wasn't human anymore.
c'était comme si elle était plus humaine.
Just an animal.
C'était qu'un animal.
And every time it went in,
À chaque coup de couteau,
she was less and less human.
elle était de moins en moins humaine.
And then...
À la fin,
she was just meat.
c'était plus qu'un bout de viande.
But she wasn't just meat, Jason.
Ce n'était pas qu'un bout de viande, Jason.
She was a person. Our film professor.
C'était une personne, notre prof de cinéma.
Yeah, well...
Oui, ben,
fuck her.
on l'emmerde.
She gave me a C-minus on my giallo paper.
Elle m'a mis C à mon dernier devoir.
ls that why you killed her? Because of the C-minus?
Tu l'as tuée pour une note ?
Who's next, your grade-school vice principal?
À qui le tour ? Le directeur de ton école primaire ?
You know who's next. Why are you being like this?
Tu sais qui ce sera. Pourquoi tu dis ça ?
Come on, Jason. How long have we known each other?
Allez, Jason. On se connaît depuis combien de temps ?
You tell me.
Dis-le-moi, toi.
Eight years. We met in junior high. In Atlanta.
Huit ans. On s'est rencontrés au collège, à Atlanta.
I just want you to tell me why you think you're doing this. In your words.
Je veux que tu me dises pourquoi tu fais ça, avec tes propres mots.
We're finishing Richie's film.
On finit le film de Richie.
That's right, by killing Sam and Tara.
Exactement, en tuant Sam et Tara.
Why are you fucking with me?
Pourquoi tu me prends la tête ?
Why won't you tell me where you are?
Dis-moi plutôt où t'es.
Why do you keep asking me that? I already told you.
Pourquoi tu redemandes ? Je t'ai déjà répondu.
I'm here.
Je suis là.
Let's play a game.
On va jouer à un jeu.
Do you know Warmer, Colder?
Tu connais le chaud-froid ?
Come on. Find me, then we'll go and cut up the Carpenter sisters.
Allez. Trouve-moi, et on ira taillader les sœurs Carpenter.
Are you using the fucking cameras?
Tu te sers des caméras ?
Yeah. The cameras.
Oui, les caméras.
And at the moment, you're very, very cold.
Pour l'instant, tu es très, très froid.
All right, douchebag, let's play.
OK, enfoiré, on va jouer.
Cold.
Froid.
Heating up.
Tu te réchauffes.
Warmer.
Tu chauffes.
All right, you know what? This is stupid. I'm gonna hang up now.
Bon, c'est débile. Je raccroche.
But you're getting warmer.
Mais tu te réchauffes.
Colder.
Tu te refroidis.
Warmer.
Tu te réchauffes.
You're on fire!
Tu brûles.
Oh, fuck!
Putain !
Do you feel like an animal, Jason?
Ça fait quoi, d'être un animal ?
Like meat?
Un bout de viande ?
But we have to finish the movie.
On doit finir le film.
Who gives a fuck about movies?
On s'en fout, des films !
So how are the new meds treating you?
Le nouveau traitement vous convient ?
Okay, I think.
Ça va, je crois.
Still not seeing anyone I shouldn't be.
Je n'ai plus de visions étranges.
What I'm really worried about, though, is Tara.
Mais je m'inquiète beaucoup pour Tara.
What I'm really worried about is you.
Et moi, je m'inquiète pour vous.
You've been coming here for six months now,
On se voit depuis six mois, mais on a seulement parlé
and all we've really spoken about is how your sister isn't dealing with
de votre sœur qui ne gère pas
whatever happened to both of you a year ago.
ce que vous avez vécu ensemble, l'année dernière.
Now, you've alluded to an abusive relationship,
Vous avez fait allusion à une relation abusive avec votre père,
But every time I push you for specifics,
mais dès que je vous demande des détails,
you shut down.
vous vous fermez.
I have trust issues.
J'ai du mal à faire confiance.
If I'm going to help you,
Pour que je vous aide,
I need you to give me the details.
il va falloir que vous me racontiez.
My father was Billy Loomis.
Mon père est Billy Loomis,
He was a famous serial killer.
un célèbre tueur en série.
They made a movie about him.
Un film a été fait sur lui.
Yeah. Certainly did.
En effet.
Last year I found out that my boyfriend was also a serial killer
L'an dernier, j'ai appris que mon copain était aussi un tueur
and only dating me because he idolized my father.
qui idolâtrait mon père.
Him and his psycho girlfriend killed a bunch of people.
Lui et sa copine tarée ont tué plein de gens,
And when it got out that I'm Billy's daughter,
mais comme je suis la fille de Billy,
this crazy rumor started online
la rumeur a couru sur Internet que j'avais tout manigancé.
Richie was my boyfriend.
Richie, c'était mon copain.
But you didn't.
Mais vous n'avez rien fait.
-Of course not. -Okay.
Bien sûr que non.
He almost killed my sister and me
Il a failli tuer ma sœur, et moi avec,
before I stopped him.
avant que je l'arrête.
How did you stop him?
Comment l'avez-vous arrêté ?
Well, I stabbed him 22 times and slit his throat.
Je l'ai poignardé 22 fois et égorgé,
Then I shot him in the head.
puis je lui ai tiré dans la tête.
But that's not why I'm here.
Mais je suis pas là pour ça.
Why are you here?
Pourquoi êtes-vous là ?
Because...
Parce que...
it felt right.
ça m'a semblé naturel.
I think we're done here.
On a terminé.
What? No, you said give you details. I'm just--
Quoi ? Vous vouliez que je vous raconte...
I'm not equipped to deal with this kind of thing.
Je ne suis pas qualifié pour cela.
Please, Dr. Stone. I'm asking for your help.
Je vous en prie, Dr Stone, aidez-moi.
By law, I'm required to report this to the authorities.
Je suis contraint d'informer les autorités.
Report it? Report what?
Les informer de quoi ?
I didn't say I was gonna do anything.
Je ne vais rien faire.
Not explicitly, no.
Ce n'était pas explicite...
You know what?
Vous savez quoi ?
Forget it.
Laissez tomber.
You're just like all the others.
Vous êtes comme les autres.
Hey, you've reached Tara. Why aren't you texting me?
Portable de Tara. Envoyez un texto.
You know you're supposed to pick up when I call.
Quand c'est moi, tu décroches.
I got out of therapy early,
Je suis sortie plus tôt du psy,
so I was thinking maybe we cook dinner tonight.
je me disais qu'on pourrait manger toutes les deux.
If you want. I'll see you soon.
À tout de suite.
Tara?
Tara ?
Quinn?
Quinn ?
Were we being too loud?
On fait trop de bruit ?
Not at all. Have you seen Tara?
Pas du tout. Tu as vu Tara ?
Don't be mad.
Te fâche pas.
-Why would I be mad? -Because you get mad.
- Pourquoi ? - Tu te fâches toujours.
Is that Paul?
C'est Paul ?
Who the fuck is Paul?
C'est qui, Paul ?
Life, I have found,
Dans la vie, l'important,
is about variety.
c'est la variété.
-This one's yours. -Thanks.
- C'est pour toi. - Merci.
-Where's Tara? -She went to the Omega Kappa Beta party.
- Où est Tara ? - À la soirée Omega Kapa Beta.
I begged her not to go to that!
Je l'ai suppliée de pas y aller.
And we've now arrived at mad.
Et voilà, tu te fâches.
Do you know if she at least took her Taser?
Tu sais si elle a pris son taser ?
I cannot speak to how heavily armed Tara is at this fraternity party.
Je ne connais pas le niveau d'armement de Tara à cette soirée étudiante.
Babe, are you coming back?
Beauté, tu viens ?
-"Babe"? -I don't know.
- Beauté ? - Laisse tomber.
Is Cute Boy shirtless again?
Le BG est encore torse nu ?
-Who's Cute Boy, babe? -Always you,
- C'est qui, le BG ? - Toujours toi.
sweetie.
Mon cœur.
You guys have been checking each other out for months.
Vous vous matez depuis des mois.
Why don't you just talk to him?
Va lui parler.
Because that right there is about all the romantic interaction I'm ready for.
Je peux pas donner plus, niveau sentimental.
-I'm gonna go find Tara. -Okay.
Je vais chercher Tara.
-Be right back. -Bye.
- Je reviens. - Salut.
It doesn't bother you?
Ça te gêne pas
I mean, being at a house party
d'être à une fête étudiante
after you were almost brutally murdered at a house party?
alors que t'as failli te faire tuer à une fête étudiante ?
No, I think of it like being struck by lightning.
Non, c'est comme être touchée par la foudre.
The odds of it happening twice to the same person are extremely low.
Le risque que ça t'arrive deux fois est infime.
Guess I should stay close to you then.
Je vais rester près de toi, alors.
-Shit, I'm sorry. -Watch out.
- Pardon. - Fais gaffe.
Hi.
Salut.
How are you doing, 1?
Comment ça va, T ?
You're lying.
J'y crois pas.
No, last one's kicked.
Le dernier est à sec.
We got some hard stuff in the kitchen, though.
Y a de l'alcool fort dans la cuisine.
Frankie.
Frankie.
Tara.
Tara.
Lead the way.
Je te suis.
You Omega Beta Zeta?
T'es membre d'Omega Beta Zeta ?
No, not yet. But I might rush it.
Non, mais je vais faire la demande.
Oh, freshman. Right on!
Donc t'es en première année, cool.
Where from?
T'es d'où ?
Michigan.
Du Michigan.
You know what?
Tu sais quoi ?
I got a bottle of Fireball up in my room.
J'ai une bouteille de whisky dans ma chambre.
Fuck it. Yeah, go.
Vendu. On y va.
Oh, I don't love that.
J'aime pas ça.
Hey! You want to call it a night?
Tu veux qu'on rentre ?
I think that I'm actually still gonna hang,
Je vais rester un peu,
but you guys don't have to wait for me.
m'attendez pas.
Don't worry. I'll take care of her. I'm Frankie.
T'inquiète, je m'occupe d'elle. Je suis Frankie.
And I'm spectacularly uninterested in knowing anything about you.
Et moi, je suis complètement désintéressée par ta personne.
No, dude, Anika, I'm not that bad.
Anika, je suis pas si bourrée.
But I appreciate you looking out for me.
Mais merci de t'inquiéter.
Cheers to the dynamic duo
Trinquons au duo d'enfer
of Hortense Tower, third floor, room 315.
d'Hortense Tower, troisième étage, chambre 315.
Oh, man. Time to start making moves.
Va falloir s'y mettre.
Get you out there. Introduce you to some girls!
On va te faire rencontrer des filles.
What about her?
Elle ?
She's gorgeous.
Canon.
-Great, ask her out. -No, I can't.
- Va lui parler. - Je vais pas débarquer...
Ask her out. Ask her out.
Va lui parler !
Shut up!
Tais-toi !
Got to have confidence. Plus, look at you, man! You're a snack!
Faut croire en soi. En plus, t'es à croquer.
Practically an entire meal all on your own.
Y a de quoi boire et manger.
-Really? -Yeah. You're Ethan Landry.
- Tu crois ? - Oui, regarde-toi.
Hey, excuse me!
Excuse-moi ?
-Chad. -Howdy. How you doing?
Salut ! Comment ça va ?
My friend here, he's a snack, right?
Mon pote est à croquer, non ?
-What did that mean? -No, it's good.
- Ça veut dire quoi ? - Tout roule.
-What? -It's not bad.
- Quoi ? - Pas grave.
There's room for improvement!
Disons qu'on peut s'améliorer.
Hey, big guy, you're needed.
Gros bras, on a besoin de toi.
See ya.
À plus.
Aren't you that girl involved in that Stab shit in California last year?
T'es pas liée aux meurtres à la Stab en Californie, l'an dernier ?
No. That's a different pirate.
Non, c'est une autre pirate.
Hey, partner!
Mec.
Tara's good down here.
Tara peut rester là.
Sorry, bro, I didn't catch that.
Quoi ? J'ai pas entendu.
Yeah, you did.
Si, t'as entendu.
No, Chad.
Chad.
-It's fine. I want to. -Yeah, see, Chad?
- Tout va bien. J'en ai envie. - Tu vois, Chad ?
-It's okay. -She wants to.
- Ça va. - Elle en a envie.
-Get your fucking hands off her. -Get the fuck off me!
- Lâche-la ! - T'as un problème ? Dégage !
Guys!
Les gars !
Who the fuck are you, Risky Business?
Va te faire ! Tu crois quoi ?
Sorry to interrupt. I'm just gonna tase you in the balls real quick.
Désolée de vous interrompre. Je te tase les burnes.
Don't ever lay hands on my sister.
Ne retouche jamais à ma sœur.
You fucking bitch!
Connasse !
-Fuck you! -Sam.
Va te faire foutre !
Are you fucking kidding me?
C'est une blague ?
You're stalking me now?
Tu m'as suivie ?
Holy shit, it's that psycho girl!
C'est la cinglée.
Tara. Will you stop?
Tara, tu peux t'arrêter ?
I cannot believe you did that! You embarrassed me.
Tu m'as foutu la honte.
That guy was a dick. He was gonna take advantage of you.
Ce connard allait profiter de toi.
-So?
Et alors ?
If I want to hook up with an asshole, that's my decision!
Si je veux pécho un con, c'est mon choix !
-It's my decision. It's not about you. -Okay.
Mon choix. Ça te concerne pas.
You're out of my life for five years,
Tu disparais cinq ans
and then you can't leave me alone for five minutes.
et maintenant, tu me lâches pas cinq minutes.
Because you're not dealing with what happened to us.
Parce que tu refoules ce qui nous est arrivé.
Have you even gone to see the counselor once?
Tu as vu le psy ?
-No, I'm not going to. -Why not?
- Non, je le ferai pas. - Pourquoi ?
Because I'm uninterested in living in the past like you are.
J'ai pas envie de vivre dans le passé comme toi.
-What's that supposed to mean? -Guys, come on.
- Quoi ? - Les filles.
It means I'm not gonna let what happened to us for three days
Je vais pas laisser ces trois jours influencer le reste de ma vie.
So you're just gonna pretend it never happened.
Donc c'est jamais arrivé ?
What are you doing here, Sam? In New York.
Qu'est-ce que tu fais ici, à New York ?
You're working two shitty jobs to help with rent, whatever,
Tu cumules deux tafs, mais c'est quoi, ton plan ?
I know what I'm gonna do.
Moi, j'ai un plan.
Okay? Because I'm gonna keep going to college,
Je vais continuer la fac,
I'm gonna get my degree, and I'm gonna live my life.
décrocher mon diplôme et vivre ma vie.
My life.
Ma vie.
Okay? I know.
Je sais.
You just followed me here, and you won't let me out of your sight.
Tu m'as suivie pour continuer à me surveiller.
-I'm just trying to look out for you.
Je veux juste te protéger.
I know.
Je sais.
I know you are.
Je sais bien.
You can't do it for the rest of my life, though.
Mais tu me tiendras pas la main toute ma vie.
You have to let me go.
Il va falloir que tu me lâches.
Murderer!
Meurtrière !
What the fuck is wrong with you, bitch?
T'es malade ou quoi ?
You got a problem with me?
Arrête ! Tu veux quoi ?
You guys should stay away from her. She knows what she did.
Elle sait ce qu'elle a fait.
I didn't fucking do anything!
J'ai rien fait, putain !
Sure, bitch.
Mais bien sûr.
Walk away!
Casse-toi !
-I'm so sick of this shit. -Hey, calm down. Come on.
J'en ai marre.
Hey, I have tissues if you want tissues.
J'ai des mouchoirs, si tu veux.
I have, like, three tissues.
J'en ai trois.
I'm sorry I told Sam where you went.
Désolée d'avoir dit à Sam où t'étais.
It's fine. I just...
C'est rien.
She's all the way up my ass
Elle me lâche plus,
like usual.
comme d'hab.
I know what it's like when they hold on too tight.
Je sais ce que c'est, quand ils s'accrochent.
After we...
Après la...
lost my brother...
la mort de mon frère,
my dad wouldn't leave me alone.
mon père me laissait jamais tranquille.
He even transferred to the NYPD when I got into college, so...
Il a intégré la police d'ici quand j'ai commencé la fac.
Stalker much?
Flippant, non ?
I'm gonna go, let you guys... chat.
J'y vais. Je vais vous laisser discuter.
Thank you.
Merci.
You can...
Tu peux...
go back to your dorm.
rentrer,
I'm pretty sure the fighting is done for the day.
je pense que la baston est terminée.
That's too bad.
Dommage.
I was actually looking forward to getting some shots in while I can.
Je voulais balancer des droites.
Bring it.
Je veux voir ça.
Thank you...
Merci
for not letting me go up those stairs.
de m'avoir empêchée de monter les escaliers.
I don't know, I think I was just more messed up than I realized.
J'étais plus bourrée que je le croyais.
Survivors got to stick together.
Les survivants s'entraident.
And besides, you can do a lot better than Date Rape Frankie.
Tu peux faire mieux que Frankie l'agresseur sexuel.
Tara, you're...
Tara, tu es...
I think you're really special.
T'es une fille géniale.
I'm not messed up anymore.
J'ai dessoûlé.
Just so you know.
Juste pour info.
I forgot my phone.
Mon portable...
Did I cock-block you?
Vous alliez ken ?
-What did you just say? -I cock-blocked you.
- Quoi ? - Vous alliez ken, non ?
-I cock-blocked you, didn't I? -Immediate no.
- Pitié. - Pas du tout.
Please stop saying the word "cock."
Arrête de dire ken.
-What did you need? -My phone.
- Tu veux quoi ? - Mon portable.
-Don't ever enter a room like that again. -I won't.
- Entre pas sans frapper. - Je le ferai plus.
-No, it was rude. -I'm gonna go.
J'y vais.
But get some rest, get sober
Repose-toi, dessoûle.
and please don't kill your sister, okay? She loves you very much.
Et ne tue pas ta sœur, elle t'aime beaucoup.
-Good night! -Bye-bye.
- Bonne nuit. - Salut.
-Quinn... -I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Je suis désolée.
Careful.
Attention.
Someone might see us.
Quelqu'un pourrait nous voir.
You always say the most romantic things.
T'es toujours si romantique.
-Danny. -What?
Danny.
Can I help it if my kink is "woman who's ashamed to be seen with me"?
Mon truc, c'est les femmes qui ont honte d'être avec moi.
Come on. You know it's not that. I'm just...
Tu sais que c'est pas ça.
-not ready for-- -I know, for your sister and your friends...
- Je suis pas prête. - Je sais. Ta sœur et tes amis
to know that you enjoy physical contact with another human being.
ne doivent pas savoir que tu aimes le contact physique avec un autre humain.
I get it, I do. Your secret is safe with me.
Je comprends. Ton secret sera bien gardé.
A little thing-- It's not a big deal--
Sinon, et c'est pas grave,
I just can't help but notice that you're covered in Cherry Coke.
je remarque que tu es couverte de soda à la cerise.
I'm pretty sure it's Diet Cherry Coke, actually.
Je crois que c'est du light.
-What, you don't like it? -No, I love it! I do.
- T'aimes pas ? - J'adore.
It's a very sensual, aromatic choice.
C'est un parfum très sensuel.
Was that another conspiracy nut?
Encore un fan de théorie du complot ?
Being famous isn't all it's cracked up to be.
Être célèbre, c'est pas si cool.
And Tara's pissed at me. Again.
Tara m'en veut à nouveau.
She says she wants me to let her go.
Elle veut que je la lâche.
Yeah, family can be rough.
La famille, c'est pas facile.
Sam!
Sam !
Get up here right now!
Remonte tout de suite !
I'm standing in front of the apartment building...
Je suis devant le bâtiment
-What's going on? -...where the mutilated bodies
où deux corps mutilés...
-of two students. .. -Cute Boy. Nice.
Le BG. Sympa.
...were discovered. Their names have just been released by police.
...ont été découverts. La police vient de donner leurs noms :
Holy shit, that's that chode from our Film Studies class!
C'est le loser de mon cours de ciné
The one obsessed with Argento.
qui adore Argento.
Also found aft the scene were various Ghostface costumes,
On a retrouvé plusieurs costumes de Ghostface,
a character popularized by the Stab movie franchise.
un personnage popularisé par la franchise Stab.
Pack a bag. We leave in ten.
Fais ton sac. On part dans 10 min.
Sam! Wait, Sam!
Sam, attends.
-We're getting out of the city. -What?
- On quitte la ville. - Quoi ?
Thank you, suspicious new guy, but we got it from here.
Merci, le nouveau suspect, ça ira.
Have a good night. Get home safe. Go, go, go...
Bonne soirée, bon retour.
-Hold on. -Come on.
- Attends. - Viens.
No, wait, let's talk about this for a second.
On va en discuter un peu.
Because this might not have anything to do with us.
C'est peut-être pas lié à nous.
-Are you serious? -It's a big city!
- T'es sérieuse ? - C'est grand, ici !
It's Halloween. Everybody's wearing masks!
À Halloween, y a des masques.
-You don't know. -Tara, this isn't a coincidence.
Tara, c'est pas une coïncidence.
You knew him!
Tu le connaissais.
-Barely. -Chad, Mindy, back me up.
- À peine. - Chad, Mindy, aidez-moi.
It is a little bit...
Ça nous...
Close to home.
Rappelle des trucs.
See?
Tu vois ?
Quinn, your dad's a cop, right?
Quinn, ton père est flic ?
Can you call him and find out what's going on?
Tu peux lui demander des infos ?
Before you make the unilateral decision to abandon my college education
Avant que tu décides que je quitte la fac et l'État.
I'm calling him now.
Je l'appelle.
Thank you.
Merci.
Who is it?
C'est qui ?
Why did everyone just freak out when her phone rang?
Le téléphone vous fait flipper ?
You got to keep up, my dude.
Faut suivre, mec.
Sam?
Sam ?
My dad wants to talk to you.
Mon père veut te parler.
-Mr. Bailey, hi. -Hey, Sam.
- M. Bailey, bonsoir. - Salut, Sam.
I was actually just about to call you.
J'allais justement t'appeler.
Well, my sister thinks I'm probably overreacting.
Ma sœur pense que je panique pour rien.
No, unfortunately, you're not.
Malheureusement, non.
What do you mean? What's going on?
Qu'est-ce qui se passe ?
I'm afraid I need you to come down to the station.
Il va falloir que vous veniez au poste.
Sam, slow down.
Sam, attends.
Tara, no. Get back inside, lock the door.
Rentre et ferme à clé.
Are you serious? Now you don't want to stick together?
Sérieux ? On reste plus ensemble ?
Fine.
OK.
What the fuck?
Quoi ?
I never deleted his contact.
J'ai jamais supprimé son contact.
-This is coming from his number. -Don't pick that up.
- C'est son numéro. - Réponds pas.
Just let it ring.
Laisse sonner.
-Who is this? -Hello, Samantha.
- C'est qui ? - Bonsoir, Samantha.
Did you miss me?
Je t'ai manqué ?
I want you to think long and hard about whether you really want to do this.
Réfléchis bien avant de t'en prendre à nous,
Because the last two people that fucked with us ended up dead.
parce que les deux derniers sont morts.
You should be thanking me, Sam.
Tu devrais me remercier, Sam.
Jason and Greg were gonna kill you and your sister.
Jason et Greg allaient vous tuer, toi et ta sœur.
[ Gutted them before they had the chance.
Je les ai étripés avant.
So what? You're protecting us now?
Et donc ? Tu nous protèges, maintenant ?
Not quite.
Pas tout à fait.
I'm going to show the world who you really are:
Je vais montrer au monde qui tu es vraiment,
A liar and a killer.
une menteuse et une meurtrière.
I'm going to punish you, Sam.
Je vais te punir, Sam.
You shouldn't believe everything you read on the Internet, asshole.
Faut pas croire tout ce qu'on lit sur Internet.
Don't be cute. You're gonna pay for what you did.
Tu vas payer pour ce que t'as fait.
And I'm not gonna stop until I butcher you.
Je m'arrêterai pas avant de t'avoir massacrée,
You and anyone who gets between us.
toi et quiconque s'interposera.
You and Tara better watch your backs.
Toi et Tara, surveillez vos arrières.
You better watch yours.
Et toi, les tiens.
Come on! Run!
Viens !
Come on!
Vite !
Help! Please!
Au secours !
In there!
Là.
Please help us!
S'il vous plaît, aidez-nous !
-We were just attacked. -Call 911!
Appelez la police !
There's a fucking line here, girls.
Faites la queue.
You got a problem here, guy?
T'as un problème, toi ?
-Go out the back! -Thank you!
- Sortez par-derrière ! - Merci.
-Fuck, it's locked. -Keys! We need your keys!
- C'est fermé. - La clé !
-Look out! -Watch out!
Attention !
Run! Go! Run!
Cours !
-Going around back. -Stay back there, ma'am.
Je vais à l'arrière.
This was found next to the body at the apartment crime scene.
On a trouvé ça près du corps, dans l'appartement.
DNA says that it belonged to someone named Richie Kirsch.
L'ADN identifié est celui de Richie Kirsch.
Does that ring a bell?
Ça vous parle ?
We're familiar with him.
On sait qui c'est.
But the one that attacked us had a different mask on.
Notre agresseur avait un masque différent.
It was kind of more beat up. Like it was older.
Il avait l'air abîmé, plus ancien.
I got to ask...
Je dois vous demander.
do you have alibis for earlier tonight?
Vous avez un alibi pour ce soir ?
I was at a party with my friends.
J'étais à une fête avec mes amis.
I was at my therapist's.
J'étais chez mon psy.
I can give you his information. You can call to check if you want.
Je peux vous donner son numéro pour vérifier.
And then I met Tara at that party
Ensuite, j'ai rejoint la fête
where I tased someone.
et j'ai tasé un mec.
Unrelated.
Rien à voir.
Was that before or after this happened?
C'était avant ou après ça ?
-Murderer! -What the fuck is wrong with you, bitch?
- Meurtrière ! - T'es malade ou quoi ?
You got a problem with me?
Tu veux quoi ?
Before.
Avant.
The point is, we were with people all night.
On était accompagnées.
So, our roommate's dad
Donc c'est le père de notre coloc
just happened to pull our case.
qui, par hasard, mène l'enquête.
-That'd be a crazy coincidence, right? -Yeah.
Quelle coïncidence, non ?
The detective who had the case offered it to me
L'inspecteur qui s'en chargeait me l'a confiée
because it involves Quinn.
parce que Quinn est concernée.
But I can totally give it back if you're uncomfortable.
Mais je peux la lui rendre, si ça te dérange.
It's fine.
Non, ça va.
So if the man who attacked you did steal your license
Si l'agresseur a volé ton permis de conduire
and plant it next to the body...
et l'a posé près du corps,
it'd probably be somebody close to you.
ça doit être un proche.
How long have you known your friends?
Vous connaissez bien vos amis ?
Well, we moved here with Mindy and Chad for summer semester like six months ago.
On est arrivées avec Mindy et Chad le semestre dernier.
Quinn, Ethan, Anika-- all since then.
On a rencontré Quinn, Ethan et Anika à cette époque.
I think I can vouch for Quinn, so that's one less we have to worry about.
Je réponds de Quinn, ça fait une suspecte en moins.
Do either of you have anyone that might want to target you?
Quelqu'un voudrait-il vous menacer ?
Not anyone who's still alive.
Personne encore en vie.
Yikes.
Eh ben.
FBI's here, claiming jurisdiction.
Le FBI est là et prend le relais.
Where are they?
Ils sont où ?
Can I help you?
Je peux vous aider ?
Special Agent Kirby Reed, FBI. I work out of the Atlanta office.
Agent spécial Kirby Reed, FBI, du bureau d'Atlanta.
Oh. You lost?
Vous êtes perdue ?
Your two vics were residents of my city before they moved here for college.
Vos deux victimes viennent de la même ville que moi.
I have been investigating their online activity
Je surveillais leur activité en ligne depuis des mois.
Why?
Pourquoi ?
I take a special interest in Ghostface attacks.
Je m'intéresse de près à Ghostface.
-Kirby? -Hey, Sam.
- Kirby ? - Bonsoir, Sam.
Tara.
Tara.
You're the FBI?
C'est toi, le FBI ?
-You guys know each other? -Yeah.
Vous vous connaissez ?
We went to Woodsboro High together. She was a senior when I was a freshman.
Oui, depuis Woodsboro. J'étais en 3e, elle était en terminale.
We share a certain history, yeah.
On a un passé en commun.
I'm not trying to get into a jurisdictional pissing contest here,
Écoutez, je ne veux pas jouer à qui a la plus grosse,
I just want to help.
mais vous aider.
I'll show you mine... et cetera.
Je vous montre mon matos, etc.
Thank you.
Merci.
He left this mask at the bodega.
C'est le masque de l'épicerie.
DNA traces of two individuals,
ADN de deux individus :
Charlie Walker, Jill Roberts, both deceased.
Charlie Walker et Jill Roberts, tous deux décédés.
The Ghostface killers of 2011.
Les tueurs de 2011.
Charlie Walker gave me this.
Charlie Walker m'a fait ça.
Like I said, I take a special interest.
D'où mon intérêt particulier.
Is this the mask he was wearing when he attacked you?
Il vous a agressées en portant ce masque ?
So he's leaving them on purpose.
Il les laisse sur place exprès.
Which means whoever's doing this is a student of the killers who came before.
L'agresseur a donc étudié les tueurs précédents.
Maybe he believes Sam is the latest in a long line.
Pour lui, Sam est leur héritière.
Yeah, good luck with that.
Bon courage pour l'enquête.
We're getting out of town.
On quitte la ville.
I'm sorry, that's not possible.
Désolé, c'est impossible.
You're both persons of interest in a double homicide,
Vous êtes liées à un double homicide,
so you're not allowed to leave town. Sorry.
vous devez rester ici.
-Are you serious? -He's right.
- C'est vrai ? - Oui.
-But if we work together-- -We're going.
- Mais si on fait équipe... - On s'en va.
Here they come.
Les voilà.
Samantha, do you have an alibi for last night's murders?
Samantha ! Avez-vous un alibi ?
Tara, do you feel safe around your sister?
Tara, vous ne craignez pas votre sœur ?
Gale Weathers, Channel 4.
Gale Weathers, Channel 4.
Do you ladies think you're the reason
Pensez-vous avoir attiré Ghostface à New York ?
Nice try, sweetie, but I've done this dance before.
Bien tenté, ma belle, mais j'ai déjà donné.
-Stay away from us. -Samantha!
Laissez-nous tranquilles.
Are you still mad at me?
Vous m'en voulez encore ?
You said you wouldn't write a book about what happened.
Vous aviez promis de pas écrire de bouquin,
And then you wrote a book
mais vous l'avez écrit.
Oh, come on.
Écoute.
Somebody was gonna write about it! It's what I do.
Quelqu'un d'autre l'aurait fait. Moi, c'est mon métier.
I heard you couldn't sell the movie rights.
Pas de film, cette fois ?
It's all about true-crime limited series these days.
Ils misent plutôt sur les mini séries criminelles.
After everything we went through together.
Après tout ce qu'on a vécu ensemble.
What would Dewey think?
Que penserait Dewey ?
-That's a low blow. -So was your book.
- C'est mesquin. - Comme votre bouquin.
You called me "unstable" and a "born killer".
Vous m'avez traitée de déséquilibrée et de tueuse.
That's taken out of context.
C'est sorti de son contexte.
That's literally a quote.
Je vous cite.
You don't think what you wrote has something to do with
Votre bouquin n'aurait rien à voir
what's happening to us?
avec tout ça ?
Come on.
Viens.
Hey, I talked to Sidney.
J'ai parlé à Sidney.
-She's not coming here, is she? -No.
- Elle va pas venir ? - Non.
She sends her love, but she's taking Mark and the kids someplace safe.
Elle vous embrasse. Elle emmène Mark et les filles en lieu sûr.
She deserves to have her happy ending.
Elle mérite son happy end.
On that much, we agree.
On est d'accord sur ça.
Hey, I want to catch this fucker as much as you do!
Moi aussi, je veux arrêter cet enfoiré.
Maybe.
Peut-être.
Or maybe you're just afraid that without Ghostface in your life,
Ou alors vous craignez que sans Ghostface,
you're gonna fade away.
tout le monde vous oublie.
You fools! You're in danger!
Imbéciles, vous êtes en danger !
Can't you see? They're after you! They're after all of us!
Regardez, ils vous traquent ! Ils nous traquent tous !
Our wives, our children, everyone!
Nos femmes, nos enfants, tous !
They're here already! You're next!
Ils sont déjà là ! C'est vous, le prochain !
Who is it?
Qui est là ?
You're a day early for trick-or-treating, you know.
Vous avez un jour d'avance pour la chasse aux bonbons.
Okay, nerds, listen up!
Les geeks, écoutez-moi.
As terrifying as this all is,
Je sais que c'est terrifiant,
I'm actually glad I get a chance to redeem myself
mais je vais pouvoir me racheter
for not calling the killers last time.
de ne pas avoir deviné les derniers tueurs.
-Yep. -It's fine. Okay.
C'est pas grave.
The way I see it, someone is out to make a sequel to the requel.
Selon moi, quelqu'un veut donner une suite au requel.
What's a requel?
C'est quoi, un requel ?
You're beautiful, sweetie. Let's hold questions to the end.
Tu es mignonne. Les questions, à la fin.
Stab 7 took place in Woodsboro.
Stab 1 se déroule à Woodsboro.
Stab 2 took place in college.
Stab 2, à la fac.
So we think that the killer is trying to copy the movies?
Le tueur copierait les films ?
That is one possibility.
C'est possible.
Heroes now in college: Check.
Les héros sont à la fac : OK.
Suspicious new characters brought in to round out the suspect list
Un nouveau personnage peut devenir suspect
and/or body count:
et/ou victime.
-Check, check and check. -I don't like this.
- OK, OK et OK. - J'aime pas ça.
-But it can't just be about Stab 2. -Why not?
- Ça se limite pas à Stab 2. - Pourquoi ?
It would make sense if this were just a sequel.
Ce serait logique pour une suite, mais c'est pas ça.
But we're not in a sequel, because nobody just makes sequels anymore.
On se contente plus de faire des suites.
We're in a franchise!
On est dans une franchise,
And there are certain rules to a continuing franchise.
et il y a des règles pour que ça fonctionne.
-I had a feeling. -Rule one:
- Je me disais aussi. - Règle numéro un :
Everything is bigger than last time.
tout est multiplié.
Bigger budget, bigger cast, bigger body count.
Budget, casting, nombre de victimes,
Longer chases, shoot-outs, beheadings.
coups de feu, décapitations...
You got to top what came before to keep people coming back.
Il faut que le public revienne.
-Beheadings? -Beheadings.
- Décapitations ? - Oui.
Rule two: Whatever happened last time, expect the opposite.
Règle numéro deux : il va se passer l'inverse de la dernière fois.
Franchises only survive by subverting expectations.
Pour survivre, les franchises doivent dérouter.
If the killers last time were whiny snowflake film nerds
Les derniers tueurs étaient des cinéphiles pleurnichards
with Letterboxd accounts instead of personalities,
qui passent leur temps sur Internet.
you can bet the opposite will be true here.
Cette fois, ce sera l'opposé.
And rule three: No one is safe.
Règle numéro trois : personne n'est en sécurité.
Legacy characters? Cannon fodder at this point.
Les persos originaux ? De la chair à canon.
Usually brought back only to be killed off in some cheap bid for nostalgia.
On les fait revenir pour les tuer et raviver la nostalgie.
It's not looking too good for Gale and Kirby.
C'est pas rassurant pour Gale et Kirby.
Oh, and that's not even the worst part!
Mais c'est pas le pire.
This is the part where she tells us the worst part.
Là, elle nous balance le pire.
The worst part is,
Le pire,
franchises are just continuing episodic installments designed to boost an IP.
c'est que les films sortent à intervalles réguliers juste pour booster un concept,
Which means main characters are completely expendable now, too.
ce qui veut dire qu'on peut aussi sacrifier les persos principaux.
Laurie Strode, Nancy Thompson, Ellen Ripley,
Laurie Strode, Nancy Thompson, Ellen Ripley,
Sally Hardesty, Jigsaw, Tony Stark, James Bond...
Sally Hardesty, Jigsaw, Tony Stark, James Bond,
I mean, even Luke Skywalker! All died so their franchises could live on.
même Luke Skywalker, ils sont tous morts pour que leur franchise survive.
That means it's not just the friend group.
Y a pas que les amis qui sont menacés.
Any of us could go at any time,
N'importe qui peut mourir à tout moment,
especially Sam and Tara.
surtout Sam et Tara.
-Wait, any of us? -Yeah.
N'importe qui ?
-Am I in the friend group?
Je fais partie des amis ?
Am I one of the targets?
Je suis aussi une cible de...
Am I gonna die a virgin?
Je vais mourir puceau ?
That was a weird over share.
On en demandait pas tant,
But it brings us to our current suspects:
mais ça nous amène à nos suspects :
Ethan.
Ethan,
The shy, dorky guy who no one suspects because he's so shy and dorky.
l'intello timide jamais suspecté parce qu'il est intello et timide.
Why am I on the suspect list? Because I'm randomly Chad's roommate?
Je suis suspect car on m'a attribué la même chambre que Chad ?
Roommate lotteries can be juked.
L'attribution est trucable.
You could have fixed it to get next to us.
T'as pu te rapprocher exprès.
Quinn.
Quinn,
The slutty roommate. A horror movie classic.
la coloc chaudasse, un classique des films d'horreur.
"Sex positive," but thank you?
Sexpositive, mais merci.
How did you come to live with Sam and Tara?
Comment t'as emménagé avec Sam et Tara ?
I answered their ad online.
J'ai répondu à leur annonce en ligne.
Okay, say no more. You've already implicated yourself enough.
N'en dis pas plus, tu t'es déjà assez compromise.
It was an anonymous ad, Mindy.
L'annonce était anonyme.
And you know we vetted her. Plus her dad is a cop.
On s'est informées, et son père est flic.
And that makes it more likely that she's the killer,
Elle est encore plus suspecte,
because having a cop dad is a great cover.
c'est la caution parfaite.
Do you not remember how these movies work, Tara?
T'as oublié comment ça marche ?
Is she always like this?
Elle est toujours comme ça ?
And finally, Anika.
Et enfin, Anika.
Never trust the love interest.
Toujours se méfier des histoires d'amour.
Okay! So, we have our rules and we have our suspects.
Donc on a les règles et les suspects.
But wait. What about you guys?
Attendez, et vous ?
I think it's pretty safe to rule out the four of us
On peut nous écarter,
who went through this last year in Woodsboro.
vu ce qu'on a vécu l'année dernière.
-Agreed. -Not agreed.
- Je suis d'accord. - Pas moi.
What if the trauma you all went through caused one or more of you to snap?
Et si les traumatismes endurés faisaient craquer l'un ou plusieurs d'entre vous ?
Yeah, or the fame you got from the killings
Ou si, avec votre célébrité,
made you thirsty for more.
vous en vouliez encore ?
I mean, let's be honest here, some of the theories online about Sam are--
Pour être honnête, certaines théories au sujet de Sam...
Don't you fucking dare.
Ferme-la tout de suite.
Okay, she's right, though.
Elle a raison.
I mean, face facts,
C'est logique :
if we're all suspects, you're all suspects.
si on est suspects, vous aussi.
Remember Samantha Carpenter's alibi, the therapist?
Vous vous rappelez l'alibi de Samantha Carpenter, le psy ?
He was stabbed to death. Through the nose.
Il a été poignardé à mort dans le nez.
Through the nose. How messed up is that?
Dans le nez. C'est pas tordu, ça ?
It's pretty messed up.
C'est hyper tordu.
He turned her in for making threatening remarks, ended up dead.
Il a signalé ses propos inquiétants et il est mort.
And guess which patient's notes were stolen?
Devinez quel dossier a été volé ?
So Sam kills her own alibi and steals her own session notes?
Donc Sam tue son alibi et vole son propre dossier ?
Maybe.
Peut-être.
Another mask was found at the scene.
On a aussi trouvé un masque.
It's a DNA match for Roman Bridger.
Avec l'ADN de Roman Bridger.
The Ghostface who was directing Stab 3.
Le Ghostface qui a réalisé Stab 3.
It's like he's leaving us real-life franchise Easter eggs.
Il nous offre des Easter eggs dans la vraie vie
Like dropping the killers' masks in reverse.
en remontant l'historique des tueurs.
Almost like he's counting down to something.
C'est comme un compte à rebours.
What happens when he gets to one?
Et quand il arrivera à un ?
So we've had nine Ghostface killers so far.
Il y a eu neuf tueurs, jusqu'ici.
Nine. But I thought in the movies--
Neuf ? Dans les films...
Forget about the movies. The movies don't matter.
On s'en fiche, des films.
Look. Last year was Amber Freeman and Richie Kirsch,
Regardez. L'an dernier : Amber Freeman et Richie Kirsch.
whose masks we found at the first crime scene
Leur masque était à l'appartement,
along with the bodies of two film students who killed their professor
près des corps des deux étudiants qui ont tué leur prof
earlier the same night.
le soir même.
Then it was Jill Roberts and Charlie Walker-- theirs at the bodega.
Puis Jill Roberts et Charlie Walker, le masque à l'épicerie.
Roman Bridger was the only single Ghostface.
Roman Bridger, le seul sans acolyte,
Kudos to him for ambition.
bravo pour l'ambition.
His mask was found at the shrink's.
Son masque était chez le psy.
Which just leaves Mickey Altieri, Nancy Loomis, Stu Macher...
Il reste Mickey Altieri, Nancy Loomis, Stu Macher...
...and Billy Loomis. Number one.
Et Billy Loomis, le premier tueur
And the father of our chief suspect.
et le père de notre suspecte principale.
Well, whoever's doing this is leading us back to Sam.
Le tueur nous ramène à Sam.
I will check in later.
Je vous appelle plus tard.
And tell your daughter to stay sharp.
Prévenez votre fille :
Proximity to the Carpenters is proximity to Ghostface.
être proche des Carpenter, c'est être proche de Ghostface.
Hey, Jack? Would you call the Atlanta field office?
Jack, tu peux appeler le bureau d'Atlanta ?
Dig up what you can on Agent Reed.
Rassemble des infos sur l'agent Reed.
I think you should get out of the city.
Tu devrais quitter la ville,
You know, considering what happened to you last time.
vu ce qui t'est arrivé, la dernière fois.
I wouldn't blame you if...
Je t'en voudrais pas
you wanted to go.
si tu voulais partir.
That's very thoughtful of you...
C'est très gentil de ta part,
but I don't think I'm going anywhere.
mais j'irai nulle part.
Will you two just make out already?
Allez, embrassez-vous.
-That is so inappropriate, dude. -Oh, whatever.
- Garde tes commentaires. - Bref.
Get it over with!
Passez à l'action.
Here you go.
Tiens.
We do not have to stay here.
On est pas obligés de rester là.
Well, too bad. I insist. Safety in numbers.
Désolée, j'insiste. Le groupe nous protège.
This'll be so fun. A little slumber party with the Core Four!
Une petite soirée pyjama avec le Gang des quatre.
-"Core Four"? -Yeah.
Le Gang des quatre ?
-Did you just give us a nickname? -I sure did.
- T'as inventé un nom ? - Oui.
We've been through a lot together, and it's a pretty cool nickname.
On a vécu des trucs difficiles, et ça claque.
-That's debatable. -It's extremely debatable.
- C'est discutable. - Hyper discutable.
You can't just give yourself a nickname, dingus.
Tu peux pas t'autonommer.
Of course I can, dingus, because I just did.
Si, et je viens de le faire.
-Core Four, up top! -No.
Le Gang des quatre, tope là !
-Down low. -Get that away.
- En bas. - Dégage.
-Please, for the love of God. -Don't do it.
- Je t'en supplie. - Le fais pas.
I would like a little more respect and support
Je voudrais bien être soutenu
from my fellow members of the Core Four.
par mes camarades du Gang des quatre.
-Guys! What the hell? -We're hearing from sources...
Les gars, il se passe un truc.
that the prime suspect is none other than Samantha Carpenter,
le suspect principal est Samantha Carpenter en personne,
one of the survivors of the Woodsboro killings in 2022,
l'une des survivantes des tueries de Woodsboro en 2022.
seen here attacking a woman on the street last night.
On l'a vue attaquer une femme, hier soir.
**** is wrong with you?
T'es malade ou quoi ?
You got a problem with me? Knock it off!
Tu veux quoi ?
You guys should stay away from her. She knows what she did.
Elle sait ce qu'elle a fait.
In the wake of the Woodsboro tragedy last year, rumors sprouted online
Suite à la tragédie de l'an dernier, les rumeurs ont fleuri en ligne
that Carpenter was actually responsible for the killings,
accusant Carpenter d'être responsable des meurtres
blaming the crimes on her boyfriend, Richie Kirsch
et d'avoir fait accuser son petit ami Richie Kirsch
and teen Amber Free--
et Amber Freeman...
I know you're not a fan of the way that I've been handling things
Je sais que t'apprécies pas ma façon de gérer
and that I've been giving you a really hard time.
et que j'ai pas été facile.
But I can say that...
Mais je sais aussi
none of us can relate to what you are experiencing.
qu'on ne peut pas comprendre ce que tu vis.
And I'm really, really sorry that you have to do that alone.
Je suis désolée que tu affrontes ça seule.
It's not your fault.
C'est pas ta faute.
And I know I shouldn't care what people think.
Je devrais pas m'inquiéter de l'avis des gens.
It just sucks being this hated.
Mais c'est difficile d'être aussi détestée.
Hey. Just a reminder,
Rappelle-toi
not a single person in this room hates you.
que personne te déteste, ici.
Okay? We have all been through some fucked-up stuff,
On a tous vécu des trucs super traumatisants
and we are coping with it differently.
et on les gère différemment.
But we moved here together for one very specific reason.
Mais on est venus vivre ici pour une raison très précise.
We are a team.
On fait équipe.
We are the Core Fucking Four.
On est le Gang des quatre.
-Thank you very much. Absolutely right. - I hate myself.
- Merci. - Je me déteste.
-You said it. -That is what I'm talking about.
- Tu l'as dit. - J'aime mieux ça.
It's the Core Four.
On est le Gang des quatre.
-Say it. -No, I'm not gonna say it. Not now.
- Dis-le. - Non, pas maintenant.
-I mean, yes, we're a team, but... -It's got a nice ring to it.
- On fait équipe, mais... - Ça sonne bien.
I've been sleeping with Cute Boy from across the hall.
Je couche avec le BG d'en face.
-Boom! - fucking knew it!
Je le savais !
-I knew it, I knew it, I knew it. -You called it.
- Je le savais ! - Tu l'avais senti.
I knew it from the day you had that hickey.
Depuis le suçon.
Sales of the Ghostface Halloween mask across the tri-state area...
Les ventes du masque dans la région de New York
...In the last 24 hours have gone through the roof.
ont bondi, ces dernières 24 heures.
-I've got my mask. What about you? -You know it.
J'ai le mien. Et vous, Jay ?
-It's gonna be one spooky Halloween. - I'll say.
- Halloween sera terrifiant. - C'est vrai.
Now let's get over to Guy for a look at our weather.
Passons à la météo.
Yeah, I know she's my roommate, but you're, like, the police.
C'est ma coloc, mais toi, t'es policier.
Hey, yeah. Wassup, bitch?
Tu fais quoi, connard ?
I feel like we should high five or something.
On devrait se taper dans les mains.
-The Core Four high five, may we, please? -Don't call it that,
- Topez-la, le Gang des quatre. - Arrête de dire ce nom.
That's gross.
C'est mignon.
Sam, what the fuck?
Sam, putain.
She's really freaked out and paranoid.
Elle flippe, elle est parano.
-Babe, you gonna join me? -Hang on.
Beauté, tu viens ?
No. And don't use my good face wash. It's pH-balanced for women.
Non, et utilise pas mes produits, ils ont un pH pour les femmes.
Pick up your phone, baby.
Décroche.
Is that him?
C'est lui ?
-No, Tara. Not right now. -Hey, so what are your intentions?
- Arrête, Tara. - Quelles sont tes intentions ?
It's fine. I'll call him back.
C'est pas grave, je le rappellerai.
Poor guy.
Le pauvre.
Quinn and her gentleman caller are back at it again.
Quinn et son prétendant s'y remettent.
She's getting it, too? Okay.
Elle aussi, elle profite.
Tara, wait, wait!
Tara, attends !
Run.
Courez.
Guys, come on!
Venez !
Oh, fuck.
Putain.
Stay the fuck back!
T'approche pas !
Wait, Chad!
Attends !
-They're still up there. -Shit!
Elles sont encore là-haut.
-Do you have the keys? - left them inside!
- T'as les clés ? - Elles sont à l'intérieur !
Mindy, bathroom door. Hurry!
Mindy, la porte de la salle de bain.
Oh, fuck! That guy's dead.
Putain, il est dead !
Shit.
Merde.
Don't worry, I got you.
T'inquiète, je suis là.
-Are you fucking kidding me? -You have a better idea?
- Tu déconnes ? - T'as une meilleure idée ?
You have to come one at a time.
Passez une par une.
-You two go first. Mindy! -What? No.
Vous deux d'abord. Mindy.
Someone needs to hold the door. I'll send Anika next. Go!
Faut retenir la porte. Je m'occuperai d'Anika.
Sam, come on. Eyes on me, baby.
Sam, viens. Regarde-moi.
Keep your eyes on me.
Regarde-moi.
-Oh, my God. -I got you, baby, I got you.
Je suis là.
Baby, come on!
Chérie, allez.
It won't hold me.
Ça va pas tenir.
It ain't going anywhere. It's gonna hold you, I promise.
Elle bougera pas, ça va tenir.
I got you. You ain't going nowhere. Let's go.
Je suis là. Dépêche-toi.
-She's losing a lot of blood! -Say something more positive!
- Ça saigne vachement ! - Dis un truc plus positif.
Eyes on me, Sam. Come on, baby.
Regarde-moi.
Come on, baby. I got you.
Je suis là.
-Come on! -Let's go!
Dépêchez-vous !
-Come on, Mindy! -Let's go, we got to move!
Faut se grouiller !
Anika, come on!
Anika !
-You have to go first. - I can't.
- Passe en premier. - Je peux pas.
Look at me. You have to go.
Il le faut.
Mindy, no! I'll be right behind you, I promise.
Non ! Je te suivrai de près, promis.
-We got you. -That's it. Mindy.
- On est là. - Continue.
-Slow and steady. -We got you.
- T'arrête pas. - Ça va aller.
-Good job, baby, you gotta go. -Get over here right now!
- Dépêche-toi ! - Grouille-toi !
Anika's coming right behind you.
Anika va te suivre, elle arrive.
-Anika, come on! -Go!
Anika, vite !
-You can do it! -Come on, Anika!
Tu vas y arriver.
Oh, God! I can't do it, I can't do it.
Je vais pas y arriver !
-Don't look down! -Look at me!!
- Regarde pas en bas. - Vite !
You can do it! You're doing good.
C'est bien.
What?
Quoi ?
Anika, you have to move right now!
Anika, faut foncer ! Magne-toi !
No, God! Please, no!
Pitié !
Anika, you got to move!
Dépêche-toi !
You have to make it!
Avance vers moi !
Baby, I don't want to die!
Je veux pas mourir !
Anika, give me your hand. I got you.
Donne ta main ! Je te tiens.
Hey. You okay?
Ça va ?
This isn't your fault, Sam.
C'est pas ta faute.
But it is.
Si.
Someone took our knives,
Quelqu'un a pris nos couteaux.
so we couldn't fight back.
On pouvait pas se défendre.
I don't know who I can trust.
Je sais pas à qui faire confiance.
Then don't trust anyone. Not your friends. Not me.
Alors ne fais confiance à personne, ni à tes amis ni à moi.
Not anyone.
Personne.
I have a few more questions for you.
J'ai encore quelques questions.
Just this way, Danny.
Par ici.
Chad.
Chad.
-Where were you? -What? When?
- T'étais où ? - Quand ?
-Last night! -What? I had Econ. You know this.
- Hier soir ! - J'avais cours.
Bullshit, man! You disappear, and my sister almost gets killed!
Tu disparais, et ma sœur se fait attaquer.
Dude, I was in a study hall with a hundred other people. You can ask any of them.
J'étais dans un amphi avec 100 personnes, tu peux demander.
-Who? -Anika and Quinn.
- Qui... - Anika et Quinn.
Mindy, I'm so sorry.
Mindy, je suis désolé.
Step the fuck back.
T'approche pas.
You're at the top of my list.
T'es mon suspect numéro un.
I had Econ!
J'avais cours.
I'm gonna be right back.
Je reviens.
I'm really sorry about Quinn.
Navrée pour Quinn.
Thank you.
Merci.
Both my kids are gone.
J'ai perdu mes deux enfants.
My whole family
Toute ma famille
is gone.
est morte.
They took me off the case.
On m'a retiré l'enquête,
But I'm not gonna stop until I find him.
mais je continuerai à le traquer.
You fuck with my family...
Si tu t'en prends à ma famille,
you die.
tu meurs.
Agreed.
Bien dit.
Hey, are you okay? I came as soon as I heard.
Ça va ? Je viens de l'apprendre.
Gale, I swear to God...
Gale, je vous préviens.
Truce, okay? I'm here for whatever you need.
Je t'assure, je veux vous aider.
Okay. Nice try.
Bien tenté.
Really, I am.
Je te promets.
Okay, fine. Off the record, okay?
OK, tout restera entre nous.
Okay. Thank you.
Merci.
I'm sorry I punched you.
Désolée pour le coup de poing.
No, you're not.
Vraiment ?
I'm not.
Non.
You're the cop, right?
C'est vous, le flic ?
I did some digging on your first two victims and I found something.
J'ai investigué et j'ai trouvé quelque chose.
I know where the masks are coming from.
Je sais d'où viennent les masques.
Show me.
Dites-moi.
Ladies.
Mesdames.
Kirby?
Kirby ?
Gale.
Gale.
-She's with the FBI. -She's a child.
- Elle est au FBI. - C'est une enfant.
When did they start letting children into the FBI?
Y a des enfants au FBI, maintenant ?
-I'm 30. -Well, you look like a zygote.
- J'ai 30 ans. - Et une tête de fœtus.
I have a gun, Gale.
Je porte une arme.
Okay, fine. You're gonna want to see this, too.
Très bien. Ça va t'intéresser aussi.
Jason and Greg were little Atlanta rich boys.
Jason et Greg étaient des gosses de riches d'Atlanta.
Apparently, they used fake names to rent this place.
Ils louaient ça sous de faux noms.
How did you find it?
Comment tu l'as trouvé ?
It's called "investigative journalism" for a reason.
Ça s'appelle du journalisme d'investigation.
How didn't you find it? Weren't you tracking them?
Comment tu l'as pas trouvé ? Tu les pistais pas ?
I went through their financial records dozens of times.
J'ai épluché leurs comptes des dizaines de fois.
This was not in any of them. Doesn't make sense.
Cet endroit n'apparaissait pas. Je comprends pas.
Don't worry. I'm just really good at my job. You'll get there.
T'inquiète pas. Je fais bien mon boulot. Ça t'arrivera un jour.
What is this place? What's with all the security?
On est où ? C'est super sécurisé.
It's a movie theater.
C'est un cinéma.
It's not just a theater.
C'est plus que ça.
It's a shrine.
C'est un sanctuaire.
They've got the whole goddamn franchise.
On a toute la franchise, là.
This was Uncle Randy's.
C'était à oncle Randy.
They've got everything.
Ils ont tout.
-Is that-- -The knife I was stabbed with.
- C'est... - Le couteau qui m'a poignardée.
You all have been through so much.
Vous avez tous beaucoup souffert.
Who drew all these?
Qui a fait ces dessins ?
How'd they get all this stuff?
Où ils ont eu tout ça ?
Isn't this evidence?
C'est pas des pièces à conviction ?
Well, cops like money, and evidence can get lost pretty easily.
Les flics aiment l'argent, et les pièces à conviction se perdent facilement.
Present company excluded, of course.
Je ne parle pas de vous.
Why am I here exactly? My alibi checks out.
Pourquoi je suis là ? J'ai un alibi.
So I can keep an eye on you, roomie.
Pour que je puisse te surveiller, coloc.
The killer must have found this place before he murdered Jason and Greg.
Le tueur a dû venir ici avant de tuer Jason et Greg,
And then he took the masks off the mannequins.
et il a pris les masques sur les mannequins.
All nine, from Stu and Billy to Amber and Richie.
Il a pris les neuf : de Stu et Billy à Amber et Richie.
Hot damn! How fucking cool is this place?
Putain, quel endroit génial.
Fuck, no.
C'est pas vrai...
Fuck, yes.
Mais si.
Come on, Sam, you got to be excited to get our murder on again. Together.
Tu te réjouis pas qu'on reprenne les meurtres ensemble ?
Billy and Sam. Team Loomis.
Billy et Sam, la team Loomis.
Get ready to slice up more motherfuckers.
Prépare-toi à découper des enfoirés.
What are you doing?
Tu fais quoi ?
I don't know.
Je sais pas.
somebody killed these chuckle fucks
Quelqu'un a tué ces abrutis
and took over?
et a pris le relais ?
Someone who believes that Sam masterminded Woodsboro.
Quelqu'un qui pense que Sam a manigancé Woodsboro.
If this were a normal Stab movie, this would be the killer's lair.
Dans un Stab, ce serait le repaire des tueurs.
Which means this isn't a normal Stab movie.
Mais on n'est pas dans un Stab.
The TV that killed Stu Macher.
La télé qui a tué Stu Macher.
If you believe he's dead.
Si on croit à sa mort.
I hear you're a horror fan.
Alors, t'es fan de films d'horreur ?
It's been said.
On dit ça.
Best Nightmare on Elm Street?
Le meilleur Freddy ?
The original.
Le premier.
Best Friday the 13th?
Meilleur Vendredi 13 ?
-Part II. -The Final Chapter.
- Le deuxième. - Le Chapitre final.
Had a crush on Corey Feldman.
Je crushais sur Corey Feldman.
Okay. Respect.
OK, respect.
Psycho II  is...
Psychose 2 est...
-underrated.
Sous-estimé.
Candyman. The original or requel?
Candyman : l'original ou le requel ?
-Both.
Les deux.
Game recognize game.
Les grands esprits se rencontrent.
You okay?
Ça va ?
Sam, when do I get to be a normal person again?
Quand je vais retrouver une vie normale ?
I don't know.
J'en sais rien.
I don't want to be a part of this.
Je veux plus faire partie de ça.
I don't want to be a part of some stupid legacy because I'm--
Je veux plus faire partie de cette histoire...
Because of me.
À cause de moi.
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolée.
Just drop it, Sam.
Laisse tomber, Sam.
I got her.
Je m'en occupe.
That seemed intense.
C'était tendu.
Ever since I came back into her life, I've just...
Depuis que je suis revenue dans sa vie...
made a mess of it.
j'ai tout foutu en l'air.
Where's your mother in all this?
Et votre mère ?
She cut me off when I told Tara about Billy.
Elle refuse de me voir depuis que j'ai parlé de Billy à Tara.
Then Tara cut her off because she wouldn't talk to me,
Tara s'est éloignée d'elle parce qu'elle m'avait rejetée.
SO now neither of us have a mother.
On a perdu notre mère toutes les deux.
I'm sorry to say this, but fuck her.
Désolée, mais on l'emmerde.
My parents sucked, too.
Mes parents étaient nuls aussi.
But you can still make your own family.
Tu peux former ta propre famille,
Even if it's just with one person.
même avec une seule personne.
And if you lose that one person?
Et si tu perds cette personne ?
You just keep going.
Tu tiens le coup.
And maybe you find another loner, and you look after each other.
Tu trouves une autre âme esseulée, et vous vous épaulez.
How'd you get past what happened to you?
Comment vous avez surmonté l'agression ?
I almost died after I was stabbed.
J'ai failli mourir poignardée.
Technically, I did die.
Techniquement, j'ai été morte
For four minutes.
pendant quatre minutes.
When I recovered...
Quand je me suis remise,
I got mad.
j'étais furieuse.
I didn't want to spend the rest of my life being afraid of monsters.
Je ne voulais pas passer ma vie à avoir peur des monstres.
I wanted the monsters to be afraid of me.
Je voulais que les monstres aient peur de moi.
I like that.
J'aime bien l'idée.
Sorry to interrupt.
Désolé de vous interrompre.
Think I might have an idea about how to turn the tables on this creep.
Je crois savoir comment coincer ce con.
Yeah. We're in.
On vous suit.
Sorry, Gale. No press allowed.
Désolée, Gale, pas de journalistes.
Police business. I'm good at my job, too.
Enquête en cours. Je fais bien mon boulot.
You should have stayed with the others.
T'aurais dû rester avec les autres.
That's not gonna happen.
Jamais de la vie.
There's no point in both of us putting ourselves at risk.
Inutile de nous mettre toutes les deux en danger.
I'm not. I'm your backup.
Je le suis pas. Je te protège.
So we're really doing the phone tracing thing that never works in the movies.
On va tracer l'appel ? Ça marche jamais, dans les films.
It'll be all, "Keep him talking, Sam. Two more minutes, I've almost got him."
"Garde-le en ligne, Sam. Deux minutes et je l'ai."
And then he hangs up just before we can get a lock.
Et il raccroche juste avant qu'on l'ait repéré.
I can trace a call in under 15 seconds.
Je peux tracer un appel en moins de 15 secondes.
Well, you've got them out there as bait.
Elles servent d'appâts.
Because the killer usually calls from somewhere nearby.
Le tueur est toujours proche.
And you think they're safe because it's broad daylight in a public place?
Elles sont en sécurité de jour, dans un lieu public ?
Look, I am here, okay? And so is Bailey.
Je suis là, et Bailey aussi.
This is exactly how our Uncle Randy died.
Notre oncle Randy est mort comme ça.
Broad daylight. Public place.
De jour, dans un lieu public.
Yanked into a van. Stab, stab, stab. No more Randy.
Jeté dans un van, poignardé, et paf, plus de Randy.
Hey, Sam? Stay frosty out there, okay?
Ouvrez l'œil, d'accord ?
We're good.
Ça ira.
-You're gonna die, you know. -No, you're gonna die, Samantha!
- Tu vas mourir. - C'est toi qui vas mourir, Samantha,
Choking on your own blood while I hack up your sister.
en t'étouffant avec ton sang pendant que je trucide ta sœur.
Unless we find you first.
Sauf si on te trouve.
For a mastermind, you're not very bright.
Pour une experte, t'es pas très intelligente.
Waiting for me to call, desperately hoping I'm nearby so the police can grab me?
Décrocher en espérant que je sois dans le coin pour que la police m'arrête ?
But I'm not nearby. I'm a step ahead.
Je ne suis pas dans le coin. J'ai un coup d'avance.
Be seeing you, Samantha.
À bientôt, Samantha.
Did you get it?
Tu l'as ?
Yep. Geolocation coming through right now.
Oui. La géolocalisation se précise.
He's on the Upper West Side.
Il est dans l'Upper West Side,
He's inside an apartment building, halfway across the city.
dans un appart à l'autre bout de la ville.
-On West 96th? -How did you know that?
- Sur 96th West ? - Comment tu le sais ?
Gale.
Gale.
"No press."
"Pas de journalistes".
Bitch, last time I saw you, you were in glee club.
La dernière fois que je t'ai vue, t'étais à la crèche.
Forgive me if I don't trust you to keep them safe.
Désolée de pas te faire confiance.
-Here you go, baby. -Thanks.
- Tiens, chérie. - Merci.
My friend Danny works on the Upper West Side. He can get there quicker.
Danny bosse dans ce quartier, il y sera plus vite.
Yeah, or he could finish her off. Is it possible he's the killer?
Ou bien il l'achèvera, si c'est lui, le tueur.
Fuck. We have to get there now.
Faut qu'on se dépêche.
It's 50 blocks away. We don't even know if it's true. Sam, wait!
C'est loin, et on est sûrs de rien !
-Take a minute. -We don't have a minute.
On n'a pas le temps.
You have to trust me, we got to make the right call.
On n'a pas le droit à l'erreur.
-He's already-- -Sam!
Il est déjà...
Get in.
Monte.
What's she doing?
Vous faites quoi ?
Hey, get out of my car!
Sortez de ma voiture.
What do you think you're doing? That's an official vehicle!
C'est un véhicule de police !
Should we use the sirens?
On met la sirène ?
Did you think we'd steal a police car and not use the sirens?
Tu crois qu'on va se refuser ça ?
-Do you even have a license? -Fuck, yeah.
- Tu as le permis ? - C'est parti.
What are you doing?
Qu'est-ce que vous faites ?
It's a cop car! You can't steal a cop car!
Vous pouvez pas voler une voiture de police !
That'll be our food.
Ça doit être le livreur.
Not the food. It's for you.
Non, c'est pour toi.
Who is it?
C'est qui ?
May I ask who's calling, please?
Qui la demande ?
He says it's the killer.
C'est le tueur.
-Hello? -Hello, Gale.
- Allô. - Bonsoir, Gale.
Strange that you and I have never spoken on the phone.
On ne s'était jamais parlé au téléphone.
This is long overdue.
Il était temps.
I agree.
Je suis d'accord.
Call the police.
Appelle la police.
[ Figured after all these years...
J'ai pensé qu'après toutes ces années,
...you'd want an interview.
tu voudrais m'interviewer.
Well, you figured right.
C'est vrai.
So, what's your motive this time?
Quelle est votre motivation, cette fois ?
You angry at the movies or you just trying to stay relevant?
Un film vous a énervé ou vous voulez qu'on parle de vous ?
I could ask you the same.
Je te retourne la question.
Don't you know the legacy characters are disposable now?
Les personnages originaux peuvent mourir aussi, maintenant.
Nobody cares about last century's heroes.
On se fout des héros du siècle dernier.
-Then why bother with me at all? -Call it nostalgia.
- Alors pourquoi m'appeler ? - Par nostalgie.
Or maybe you deserve to be punished
Ou pour te punir
for all that money you made off the misery of others.
d'avoir exploité les traumatismes des autres.
Maybe it's time someone made a buck reporting your death.
Il est temps que quelqu'un gagne de l'argent en racontant ta mort.
You know you're like the tenth guy to try this, right?
Tu sais que t'es le dixième qui me fait le coup ?
And spoiler alert,
Attention, spoiler :
it never works out for the dipshit in the mask.
ça finit jamais bien pour le débile masqué.
Oh, but they certainly leave a mark before they go, don't they?
Mais il fait quand même impression, non ?
Richie and Amber managed to butcher Dewey.
Richie et Amber ont massacré Dewey
Carved him up like a Christmas goose.
en le découpant comme une dinde de Noël.
How does it feel to lose the only man who ever loved you?
Ça fait quoi de perdre le seul homme qui t'ait aimée ?
Fuck you!
Va te faire foutre !
How does it feel to know that you weren't there for him at the end?
Ça fait quoi de ne pas avoir été là, quand il est mort ?
Not there to give him comfort
Tu n'étais pas là pour le réconforter
as he died screaming in his own guts.
quand il a crevé en crachant ses viscères.
You're the one who's gonna die screaming.
C'est toi qui vas crever.
Maybe. But you won't be around to see it.
Peut-être, mais tu ne seras pas là pour le voir.
You couldn't stop what happened to Dewey.
Tu n'as pas pu sauver Dewey
Just like you're not gonna be able to stop this.
et tu n'empêcheras pas ça.
How's that for nostalgia, fucker?
Ça te rend nostalgique, ça, connard ?
You missed.
Tu m'as raté.
Sure I did.
Mais bien sûr.
You win. I'm in the elevator heading for the ground floor.
T'as gagné. J'ai pris l'ascenseur, je descends.
Sure you are.
Je te crois.
Maybe you did hit me. Maybe I'm wounded.
Tu m'as peut-être blessé.
Or maybe I'm wearing a bulletproof vest.
Ou je porte peut-être un gilet pare-balles.
That's why I'm gonna shoot you in the fucking head!
C'est pour ça que je vais t'exploser la tête !
You would've made a good killer, Gale.
Tu aurais fait une très bonne tueuse, Gale.
Sidney never would've made sense and Dewey was the fan favorite.
Sidney, pas crédible, Dewey, le chouchou des fans,
But you cracking under the pressure
mais toi, qui craques sous la pression
and turning into Ghostface would've been a great twist.
et qui deviens Ghostface, le rebondissement parfait.
Keep talking, asshole.
Cause toujours, ducon.
Sure. What do you want to talk about?
Avec plaisir. Tu veux parler de quoi ?
You never got to be the leading lady, did you?
Tu n'as jamais eu le premier rôle.
It was always all about poor sweet Sidney, sucking up all the oxygen.
On ne parlait que de la pauvre petite Sidney qui prenait toute la place.
What did that leave you to be?
Et toi, il te restait quoi ?
The brains and the sex appeal.
L'intelligence et le sex-appeal ?
Sorry about your boyfriend.
Désolé pour ton copain.
All those muscles didn't help much.
Ses muscles ne l'ont pas beaucoup aidé.
They sure didn't.
Je vois ça.
Can you hold, please?
Ne quitte pas.
Fuck you!
Va te faire foutre !
Hey, fuckface!
Connard !
Sorry.
Pardon.
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolée.
I should've known that he was gonna come after you.
J'aurais dû deviner qu'il vous ciblerait,
I'm so sorry.
je suis désolée.
He didn't get me.
Il ne m'a pas eue.
Tell Sidney
Dis à Sidney
he never got me.
qu'il ne m'a pas eue.
Gale? Please.
Je vous en supplie.
Out of the way!
Poussez-vous.
-Out of the way! -Move. You got to move. Move!
Il faut s'écarter.
-Get them back. -Sam, please!
- Éloigne-les. - Elles doivent reculer.
-They need to move now. -Please step back.
Venez.
-Call it in. -Right away.
- Préviens-les. - Tout de suite.
-Checking. -Come on, Gale.
Je vérifie.
Got a weak pulse. Get the backboard.
Le pouls est faible, amène la civière.
We need to move now.
Faut l'emmener tout de suite.
Backboard! Let's move.
Civière. On se dépêche.
I got here as fast as I could.
J'ai fait au plus vite.
Did you?
T'es sûr ?
I'm scared, you guys.
J'ai peur.
I really don't want to get hurt again.
Je veux pas être encore attaquée.
Neither do I.
Moi non plus.
I don't want you getting hurt again, either.
Je veux pas que tu sois attaqué.
I know. I know.
Je sais.
So what do we do now?
On fait quoi ?
Maybe he gets to win this time.
Il va peut-être gagner, cette fois.
He wants to punish me.
C'est moi qu'il veut punir.
Me.
Moi.
So maybe I let him.
Je peux le laisser faire.
I'll just give myself up.
Je me sacrifie.
If this is what I have to do
Si c'est ce que je dois faire
to keep you safe...
pour vous protéger,
it's worth it.
ça vaut le coup.
No, we're not doing that, Sam.
Hors de question, Sam.
You went back to Woodsboro to protect me.
T'es revenue à Woodsboro pour moi.
Every single day, you make the decision to protect me.
Tous les jours, tu décides de me protéger.
None of us would even be alive if it weren't for you.
Aucun de nous ne serait en vie, sans toi.
You have to let us protect you this time.
Cette fois, on te protège.
We're a team, remember?
On est une équipe.
Actually...
En fait,
we're a family.
on est une famille.
Let's go! Core Four! Come on.
Le Gang des quatre ! Allez.
-Core Four. -Come on.
Le Gang des quatre.
-Core what? -It's an us thing.
- Le quoi ? - C'est perso.
He's gonna keep coming after us.
Il va continuer à nous traquer.
Isn't there somewhere that's safe we could just hole up in?
Y a pas un endroit où on peut se cacher ?
No, he's just gonna keep finding us.
Il nous trouvera toujours.
Great.
Super.
We could use that, though.
Mais ça peut nous être utile.
I'm getting my ass chewed out for not dropping the case
On me force à lâcher l'enquête,
and now you want me to do what?
et vous voulez faire quoi ?
We want to lure him to a secure location and trap him inside.
L'attirer quelque part pour le piéger.
And then what?
Et ensuite ?
We execute him.
On le tue.
Are you gonna help us?
Vous allez nous aider ?
Let's kill the son of a bitch.
Butons cet enfoiré.
Now, I'm stuck here, but Gale gave us the key cards to the theater.
Je dois rester ici, mais on a les badges du cinéma.
It's got heavy surveillance and security cameras, but we can use that against him.
Il y a des tas de caméras, mais on les utilisera contre lui.
[I tell Kirby to meet you there and I'll join you as soon as I can.
Je dis à Kirby de vous rejoindre et j'arrive.
-Got it. -And remember, travel in public.
- Compris. - Utilisez les transports en commun.
The more people around you, the less chance he has
Plus vous serez entourés, moins il pourra
lo lake a shot at you before you get there.
vous attaquer en chemin.
Is this even a good plan?
C'est une bonne idée ?
You don't have to come if you don't want to.
Personne te retient.
So we just peel off and the killer picks us off one by one? No, thank you.
On se sépare, et il nous cueille un par un ? Non merci.
Let's just get to the theater. Come on, in here.
On va au cinéma. Montez.
Yes, because it'll be much less scary at the serial killer movie theater.
On flippera moins dans le ciné du tueur.
-Wait, where's Mindy? -Chad! Sam! Hey, Sam!
Où est Mindy ?
Let's go. Shit.
Viens ! Merde.
Fuck!
Putain !
Get your Ghostface ass away from me, Ghostface.
Casse-toi, avec ta tronche de Ghostface.
Go away.
Regarde ailleurs.
-Where's Mindy? -She missed the train.
- Et Mindy ? - Elle a raté la rame.
I was gonna wait for her, but Cute Boy here dragged me on.
Il m'a tiré par le bras.
- I was trying to keep us together. -By pulling us apart?
- Restons ensemble. - En nous séparant ?
It's okay.
OK, c'est rien.
This is a South Ferry bound local one train.
Ce train est à destination de South Ferry.
Oh, shit.
Merde.
The next stop is 79th Street.
Le prochain arrêt est 79th Street.
How many stops do we have?
Combien d'arrêts ?
Ten.
Dix.
This is 79th Street.
79th Street.
This is a South Ferry bound local one train.
Ce train est à destination de South Ferry.
The next stop is 72nd Street.
Le prochain arrêt est 72nd Street.
This is a South Ferry bound local one train.
Ce train est à destination de South Ferry.
The next stop is 79th Street.
Le prochain arrêt est 79th Street.
Sorry!
Déso.
Still nothing from Mindy.
Elle répond pas.
This is 72nd Street.
72nd Street.
Guys?
Les gars.
The next stop is 66th Street, Lincoln Center.
Le prochain arrêt est 66th Street, Lincoln Center.
Fuck you.
Connard.
This is a South Ferry bound local one train.
Ce train est à destination de South Ferry.
The next stop is 66th Street, Lincoln Center.
Le prochain arrêt est 66th Street, Lincoln Center.
This is 66th Street, Lincoln Center.
66th Street, Lincoln Center.
As you exit, please be careful of the platform and the train.
Attention à la marche en descendant du train.
Shit, shit. Mindy!
Merde, Mindy !
Fuck, that's a lot of blood.
Ça saigne trop.
Help! Somebody help!
Aidez-moi !
Fuck. We got to get you out of here, okay?
On va te sortir de là.
-Come on! -Fuck!
Viens.
Shit. Somebody call 911!
Appelez les secours !
-Oh, my God. -Are you okay?
Ça va ?
Yeah, I'm so good.
Oui, super.
You're gonna be okay.
Ça va aller.
Goddamn it. I got it wrong again.
Putain, je me suis encore trompée.
What the fuck?
Bordel.
Help!
Aidez-nous !
Yeah, we need medical assistance We're at the 66th Street station.
Faites venir les secours, station 66th Street.
Fuck this franchise.
Franchise à la con.
I talked to Bailey. I've got everything set up.
J'ai parlé à Bailey, tout est prêt.
-Where are Mindy and Ethan? -They're five minutes behind us.
- Où sont Mindy et Ethan ? - Ils arrivent dans cinq minutes.
Let's get you all inside.
On se rassemble tous là-bas.
-Not you. -What?
- Pas toi. - Quoi ?
Don't trust anyone, remember?
"Fais confiance à personne."
We don't know you.
On te connaît pas.
Not really.
Pas vraiment.
You know me.
Toi, tu me connais.
You're not Woodsboro.
T'es pas de Woodsboro.
I'm sorry.
Je suis désolée.
It's okay. It's okay, I get it.
C'est rien, je comprends.
Be safe, okay?
Fais attention à toi.
You, too.
Toi aussi.
Good call.
T'as bien fait.
I cleared the whole place before you got here.
J'ai vérifié tout le bâtiment.
So, this is the only way in or out.
C'est la seule entrée et sortie.
He steps in through the first door,
Il ouvre la première porte,
both doors lock automatically, trapping him inside.
les deux portes se verrouillent et l'enferment.
We turn it into a kill box.
Ça devient une kill box.
-Weapons? -One gun, and I hold onto it.
- Des armes ? - Moi seule ai un revolver.
I am the only one with a badge here and that's the way it's gonna be.
Je suis la seule habilitée, c'est comme ça.
We're safe here.
On est en sécurité.
I'm gonna check in with Mindy. See if they're close.
Je vais appeler Mindy, voir s'ils arrivent.
Hey, you've reached me. Leave a message.
Salut, c'est moi. Laissez un message.
You know you're not safe here.
Vous êtes pas en sécurité.
Whenever someone says, "We're safe here," it means you're not.
Si quelqu'un le dit, c'est que c'est faux.
-Not now. -But you're smarter than this, Sam.
- Pas maintenant. - T'es plus maligne que ça.
Grab a weapon and clear this place yourself.
Prends une arme et vérifie par toi-même.
You know I'm right.
Tu sais que j'ai raison.
Excellent choice.
Un excellent choix.
My favorite.
C'est mon préféré.
Kirby?
Kirby ?
Get everyone out of there, Sam, you're not safe.
Sortez de là, c'est dangereux.
[ Heard from the Atlanta field office.
D'après le bureau d'Atlanta,
They said Agent Reed's been on a downward spiral
l'agent Reed va très mal
ever since the Woodsboro murders last year.
depuis Woodsboro, l'an dernier.
What are you talking about?
Quoi ?
They fired Kirby two months ago for being mentally unstable.
Elle a été virée il y a deux mois pour troubles mentaux.
-What? -She's no longer with the FBI.
- Comment ça ? - Elle n'est plus au FBI.
-Listen, asshole. -No, you listen, you little bitch.
- Écoute-moi, enfoiré. - Petite conne,
Hang up on me, [I gut you like a fish. Understand?
si tu raccroches, je te vide comme un poisson.
- What do you want? - To see what your insides look like.
- Tu veux quoi ? - Voir à quoi ressemblent tes viscères.
When was the last time anybody used this place?
Depuis quand ce ciné est fermé ?
It's so old.
Tout est super vieux.
I'm sorry, you can have them.
Désolé, prends-les.
-Take them. -No, I mean...
Vas-y, toi.
If you want them, you have them.
Si tu les veux, prends-les.
-You think I want these? -Kind of.
- Je voudrais ça ? - Je crois.
They're a hundred years old.
Ils ont un siècle.
Maybe that's your thing.
Mais si ça te tente...
It's maybe embarrassing how long I've wanted to do that.
J'avais envie de faire ça depuis tellement longtemps.
You should've done that a lot sooner.
T'aurais pu te décider plus tôt.
I know.
Je sais.
But you could also do it a lot more times.
Tu le referas plein de fois.
Tara, let's go. Come on, come on!
Tara, viens, vite !
Come on, go, go, go!
Vite !
-It's Kirby. She's the killer. -No shit.
- C'est Kirby, la tueuse. - Merde.
-That's locked. Come on. -Are we trapped?
- C'est fermé. - On est piégés ?
She made this whole theater a kill box. For us.
La kill box, elle est pour nous.
Hey, what about that? There's an exit door.
Et là-haut ? Y a une sortie.
Maybe it leads to the roof or something?
Ça donne sur le toit ?
There's only one way to find out. Let's go.
On verra bien, venez.
Bailey's on the way, but--
Bailey va arriver.
Beheadings!
Décapitations !
Tara! Come on.
Tara, viens !
Smile for the camera, motherfucker!
Souris, t'es filmé, connard !
This way! Come on!
Par là !
She should be running out the front door.
Elle ferait mieux de sortir !
Get fucked!
Magnez-vous !
Tara, go! Go!
Tara, recule !
Run.
Courez.
Go.
Partez.
-This way. Up here. Come on. -...like a Wes Carpenter flick.
Par ici.
Everybody's a suspect.
Tout le monde est suspect.
You're not scared, are you?
T'as pas peur, quand même ?
It's a lot scarier when there's no motive.
C'est plus flippant quand y a pas de mobile.
Ready?
Prête ?
I need you to be ready. Ready?
Reprends-toi. Prête ?
Look at me.
Regarde-moi.
I'm ready.
Je suis prête.
Come on, motherfucker!
Viens là, enfoiré !
It's okay!
Pas de panique.
-Stay the fuck back! -We know it's you, Kirby.
- Approche pas. - On sait que c'est toi.
One of them knocked me out.
L'un d'eux m'a assommée.
Kirby, stop! Get away from the girls!
Kirby, arrêtez. Écartez-vous des filles.
What are you doing?
Vous faites quoi ?
Did you kill Quinn? Did you kill my daughter?
Vous avez tué Quinn ? Vous avez tué ma fille ?
Jesus Christ!
Bordel !
Whatever he's been saying to you, don't listen to him.
Je sais pas ce qu'il a raconté, mais le croyez pas !
He's probably the killer.
C'est sûrement le tueur.
Behind you!
Derrière vous !
Great job.
Beau boulot.
Both of you.
Tous les deux.
-You? -Yeah, of course me.
- Vous ? - Eh ouais.
Frankly, I expected more from the two of you after what you did to us.
Vous m'avez déçu, après ce que vous nous avez fait.
What do you mean, "us"?
Qui ça, "nous" ?
Mindy was right. It was easy to juke the roommate lottery.
Mindy avait raison. J'ai truqué l'attribution des colocs.
All I had to do to meet you
Pour vous rencontrer,
was room with a conceited, condescending alpha literally named Chad.
il suffisait de vivre avec un mâle alpha arrogant avec un nom à la con comme Chad.
Fuck, it felt good to kill him!
J'ai adoré le buter !
This was your grandmother's, Sam.
C'était à ta grand-mère, Sam,
Nancy Loomis?
Nancy Loomis.
Really runs in your fucking family, doesn't it?
C'est vraiment de famille, putain.
-Speaking of family... -Wait for it.
- En parlant de famille... - Surprise.
...my name's not Ethan Landry...
Je m'appelle pas Ethan Landry.
is it, Dad?
N'est-ce pas, papa ?
"Dad"?
"Papa" ?
Wait. If it's you two, that just leaves...
Attendez. En dehors de vous, il reste juste...
Mindy?
Mindy ?
Hey, roomies.
Salut, les colocs.
You didn't see that one coming, did you?
Vous vous y attendiez pas.
-Yeah, because you died! -Kind of didn't, though.
- Parce que t'es morte ! - Pas vraiment, en fait.
It was a good way to get off the suspect list,
C'était efficace pour ne plus être suspecte,
stab Gale Weathers, stab Mindy on the train. That sort of thing.
pour poignarder Gale Weathers, et Mindy dans le métro, ce genre de trucs.
Yep, and I just made sure I was first on the scene
Je suis arrivé en premier
so I could switch her body out with a fresh one.
pour la remplacer par un macchabée.
A little fake blood, a prosthetic.
Un peu de faux sang, des prothèses.
You'd be amazed at what a grieving father can get away with.
C'est fou comme on passe tout à un père en deuil.
I got Stu Macher's mask.
J'ai le masque de Stu Macher.
He was my favorite.
C'était mon préféré.
Nice. That's number three.
Parfait. C'est le numéro trois.
That's two.
Ça, c'est le numéro deux.
Which leaves...
Et il reste
your father's.
ton père.
This is what we've been counting down to, Sam.
Voilà où nous mène le compte à rebours.
I'm gonna need you to put it on.
Tu vas devoir le mettre.
Fuck you!
Va te faire !
Stay the fuck away from her!
L'approche pas !
Come on.
On se calme.
What? What is this?
C'est quoi, votre délire ?
You did this as a family?
Vous faites ça en famille ?
Hell yeah, bitch! You should know better than anyone.
Oui, connasse. Ça te rappelle rien ?
They're still not getting it.
Elles captent pas.
I don't know what you believe,
Je sais pas ce que vous croyez,
but I didn't commit those murders in Woodsboro. It wasn't me!
mais j'ai tué personne à Woodsboro, c'était pas moi !
We know that. Of course you didn't.
On le sait !
You think this is based on some bullshit conspiracy theory?
Tu crois qu'on fait ça à cause d'une théorie du complot débile ?
Come on. Who do you think started the rumors about you in the first place?
Réfléchis. Qui a lancé les rumeurs à ton sujet ?
Do you know how easy it was
Tu sais comme c'est facile
to turn Sam from the hero of Woodsboro into the villain?
de faire de l'héroïne de Woodsboro une méchante ?
How easy it is to convince the world
Comme c'est facile de pousser le monde entier
to believe the worst in people rather than the best?
à croire le pire, plutôt que le meilleur ?
Because it's not enough to just kill someone these days.
Ça suffit plus, de tuer quelqu'un, de nos jours.
You have to assassinate their character first.
Il faut assassiner sa réputation, d'abord.
So when Dad here "discovers” your horribly mutilated bodies...
Quand papa découvrira vos corps déchiquetés
posed with Sam wearing her father's mask,
et Sam avec le masque de son père,
he'll say some poor dumb bastard read on the Internet
il dira qu'un abruti a lu sur Internet
that you're the real Ghostface
que c'est toi, Ghostface,
and took matters into their own deluded hands.
et qu'il a voulu rendre justice.
Exactly! That's why it's the perfect alibi.
Exactement. C'est l'alibi parfait.
And all the best lies are based on the truth.
Tout bon mensonge a une part de vérité.
And you're a killer.
Tu es une tueuse.
-Just like your father. -No, I'm not!
- Comme ton père. - C'est faux !
Yes, you are, you motherfucker! You killed our brother!
Si, connasse, t'as tué notre frère !
What are you talking about?
Quoi ?
You said your brother died in a car accident.
T'as parlé d'un accident de voiture.
No, no, no, you sweet, dumb thing.
Non, petite imbécile.
He died in Woodsboro...
Il est mort à Woodsboro,
at the hands of your bitch sister.
des mains de ta salope de sœur.
You're Richie's family.
Vous êtes la famille de Richie.
Yeah.
Oui.
Go! Go!
Vite !
-Now she's finally starting to get it. -Now!
- Elle capte enfin. - Maintenant !
It wasn't until I saw that photograph
C'est en voyant la photo
of what you'd actually done to him that I knew.
de ce que tu lui as fait que j'ai su
That I knew you had to fucking die! You had to be punished!
que tu devais mourir, être punie,
Along with anyone else who stands in our way.
comme tous ceux qui nous font barrage.
There she is.
La voilà.
There's the fucking killer.
Elle est là, notre tueuse.
-Great parenting job, by the way. -Shut your whore fucking mouth!
- Très bon père. - Ferme ta gueule !
Have I been a perfect dad? No.
Suis-je un père parfait ? Non.
Have I maybe overindulged Richie's love of these little movies? Yeah, maybe.
Ai-je trop laissé Richie regarder ces films ? Oui, peut-être.
For me, they're just a little dark.
Moi, je les trouve sinistres.
But...
Mais...
Richie really loved them.
Richie les adorait.
He loved them!
Il les adorait.
He even made a few of his own.
Il réalisait ses propres films.
Did you know? Did you know?
Vous le saviez ?
So you think I didn't post a holiday special.
Vous croyez que j'ai rien posté à Noël,
Well, I tried to. I really did try.
mais j'ai essayé, j'ai vraiment essayé.
There's a very special bond between a father
Il y a un lien très fort entre un père
and his first son.
et son fils aîné.
Which is why I helped him build this collection.
Je l'ai aidé à réunir cette collection.
This was... all his?
Tout ça, c'est à lui ?
Yes, he's a very passionate collector. And he inspired others.
Un collectionneur passionné. Il faisait des émules.
We had to kill those two wannabe film students because, well...
Il fallait éliminer les deux étudiants en cinéma parce que...
we had to kill you first, Sam.
c'est nous qui devions te tuer.
I put the theater in their name,
J'ai loué le cinéma à leurs noms.
then good ol' Detective Bailey would've just stumbled on it
Je n'ai pas eu le temps de feindre de le découvrir
but I didn't have to because, by golly,
parce que Gale Weathers est une sacrée journaliste.
I built a tribute to my son.
J'ai voulu rendre hommage à mon fils.
Which is why this is where you have to die, Sam...
Donc tu dois mourir ici, Sam,
surrounded by all the things he loved the most.
entourée de ses objets préférés.
What happens next? After you're done with us you just disappear?
Et ensuite ? Vous nous tuez et vous disparaissez ?
No! We got to hurry over to the hospital
Non, on va à l'hôpital pour s'assurer
and make sure Mindy and Gale don't pull through.
que Mindy et Gale meurent.
Because everybody dies, Sam!
Tout le monde crève !
Everyone who had anything to do with the death of my son suffers and dies.
Tous ceux liés à la mort de mon fils souffrent et meurent.
Fuck yeah, they do!
Grave.
Now put on the mask.
Mets le masque.
He was...
Il était
so pathetic.
tellement pathétique.
That's not true.
C'est faux.
Yeah, your son...
Si, votre fils.
he was a man-baby who made his girlfriend do all the killing.
C'était un gros pleurnichard qui a laissé les meurtres à sa copine.
He was a strong, virile young man!
C'était un jeune homme fort et viril.
He was a limp-dick little fuck who cried before I slit his throat.
C'était une couille molle qui a chialé quand je l'ai égorgé.
Shut the fuck up!
Ta gueule !
Sam, come on!
Sam, vite !
Recognize this?
Tu le reconnais ?
Fuck you!
Va chier !
Sorry, but I kind of need this.
Désolée, j'ai besoin de ça.
Fuck him up.
Défonce-les.
What are you gonna do about it, bitch?
Tu vas faire quoi ?
I'll get help.
J'appelle les secours.
Be careful.
Fais attention.
Go get her. Get her!
Occupe-toi d'elle.
-I can't grab you. -It's okay.
- Je tiens pas. - Ça va aller.
I can't grab on. I can't grab on.
J'y arrive pas. J'y arrive pas.
I've always wanted to stick something in you, Tara.
Je vais enfin t'en mettre un coup.
-Fuck you!
Va chier !
You guys are so fucked now!
Vous êtes foutues, maintenant.
-Let me go. -No!
Lâche-moi.
Yeah, let her go, Sam, come on.
Allez, Sam, lâche !
-Trust me. -Fuck!
Fais-moi confiance.
You have to let me go.
Il faut que tu me lâches.
Gotcha!
Je t'ai eue !
Now die a fucking virgin.
Tu vas crever puceau.
Looks like you're down another brother.
T'as perdu un deuxième frère.
Always got to shoot them in the head.
Faut toujours viser la tête.
Hello, Detective Bailey. I've got one question for you.
Bonsoir, lieutenant Bailey. J'ai une question à te poser.
What's that?
Laquelle ?
What's your favorite scary movie?
C'est quoi, ton film d'horreur préféré ?
"Favorite scary movie."
Mon film d'horreur préféré.
I'm asking because you're in one now.
Tu es dans un film d'horreur, là.
You're in my movie.
Et c'est mon film.
I see you've put on your true face, huh?
Je vois que tu as pris ce qui te revenait,
Your birthright.
ton héritage.
Poetic that you're gonna die in it.
C'est poétique que tu meures avec.
This is what you wanted, isn't it?
C'est ce que tu voulais, non ?
Now you know the truth, huh?
Tu connais la vérité.
Murder's in your blood!
Tu as le meurtre dans le sang.
Stop fucking around and show yourself!
Arrête tes conneries et montre-toi !
Be careful what you wish for.
Je serais toi, je dirais pas ça.
All right, I'm a fucking police officer.
Je suis flic, merde !
How do you think this is gonna go, Sam? Who do you think they're gonna believe?
Tu crois que ça finira comment ? À ton avis, ils vont croire qui ?
Probably the one who's still alive.
Sûrement le survivant.
My father was a murderer.
Mon père était un meurtrier.
No matter what you think,
Quoi que tu en penses,
I'm better than that.
je vaux mieux que ça.
Thank you.
Merci.
But you did fuck with our family, so...
Tu t'en es pris à notre famille...
-Nice. -Thanks.
- Joli. - Merci.
You okay?
Ça va ?
No.
Non.
Thank you for letting me go.
Merci de m'avoir lâchée.
I knew you could take care of yourself.
Je savais que tu t'en tirerais.
I want to be in your life,
Je veux faire partie de ta vie,
but only as much as you want me to be.
mais c'est toi qui décides.
I want you to be.
Je veux que t'en fasses partie.
I promise you I'm gonna get so much therapy after this.
Promis, je vais faire une longue thérapie.
I'm serious.
Je te jure.
We're gonna get through this.
On va s'en sortir.
Together.
Ensemble.
I saw that in a scary movie once.
J'ai vu ça dans un film d'horreur.
-Are you okay? -Yeah.
- Ça va ? - Oui.
I thought you might need some reinforcements.
J'ai fait venir du renfort.
And I called Mount Sinai, and Mindy and Gale are gonna be okay.
J'ai appelé l'hôpital, Mindy et Gale vont s'en sortir.
Mindy's on her way here now. They couldn't stop her.
Mindy arrive, personne a pu la retenir.
Not bad, Cute Boy.
Pas mal, BG.
Thanks.
Merci.
If you ever need me, call.
Si jamais vous avez besoin, appelez-moi.
We're all part of the same fucked-up family now.
On forme une grande famille de dingues.
And legacy doesn't always have to be a bad thing.
La famille, c'est pas forcément une mauvaise chose.
It's just Chad.
C'est Chad.
Hey, we got another one here!
On a quelqu'un d'autre.
Watch out, coming through.
Attention.
How are you alive?
Comment t'as survécu ?
Core Fucking Four.
Le Gang des quatre.
Sorry. You probably need that.
Désolée, t'as besoin de ça.
Oh, my God! Are you guys okay?
Vous allez bien ?
I know who the killer is! It's Ethan and Bailey.
Les tueurs, c'est Ethan et Bailey.
-And Quinn. -And Quinn? Fuck!
- Et Quinn. - Et Quinn ? Putain !
Did I miss the monologue again?
J'ai encore raté le monologue ?
Are you okay? Are you okay?
Ça va ?
You don't look okay.
On dirait pas.
Oh, my God, we all survived. It's a twist on a twist.
On a tous survécu, double rebondissement.
They gave me a lot of drugs. You guys should get some of these drugs.
On m'a complètement shootée. Vous devriez essayer.
I can't feel anything below my shoulders.
Je sens plus mon corps.
Coming?
Tu viens ?
Not every movie needs a post-credit scene.
Ça suffit, les scènes post-générique !